<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-12-12T13:23:24+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">glenelg.io</title><subtitle>Glenelg.io, a site set aside for writing, sharing, grumbling and (maybe) ranting. I&apos;m Fraser Smith, a freelance developer and amateur photographer living in Shanghai.
</subtitle><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><entry><title type="html">Switching From Windows To Linux</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/12/switching-from-windows-to-linux" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Switching From Windows To Linux" /><published>2022-12-12T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-12-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/12/switching-from-windows-to-linux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/12/switching-from-windows-to-linux"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Buying a Pico 4 VR from China</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/21/buying-a-pico-4-from-china" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Buying a Pico 4 VR from China" /><published>2022-10-21T19:15:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-10-21T19:15:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/10/21/buying-a-pico-4-from-china</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/21/buying-a-pico-4-from-china"><![CDATA[<p>The Pico 4 VR headset as just launched globally and it’s causing quite a stir. It has been available on the Chinese market for a few weeks now and you may have opted to order one direct from China to take advantage of the lower price and better availability. Then you receive it and discover that the Pico store and user accounts are geographically locked for the Chinese market.
<!--more--></p>]]></content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="vr" /><category term="PicoVR" /><category term="China" /><category term="AliExpress" /><category term="Quest2" /><category term="Meta" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Pico 4 VR headset as just launched globally and it’s causing quite a stir. It has been available on the Chinese market for a few weeks now and you may have opted to order one direct from China to take advantage of the lower price and better availability. Then you receive it and discover that the Pico store and user accounts are geographically locked for the Chinese market.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back to Glenelg</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/01/back-to-glenelg" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back to Glenelg" /><published>2021-05-01T14:20:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-05-01T14:20:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/01/back-to-glenelg</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/01/back-to-glenelg"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/glenelg-banner.jpg" alt="Old Map of Glenelg" />
<em>Those who know me well enough to communicate via email, know that I my personal domain that I use for email is <strong>glenelg</strong>. Very few, however, are aware of my reason for using this domain name. In this post, I hope to explain why (and it’s not just because it’s a very cool palindrome).</em>
<!--more--></p>]]></content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="glenelg" /><category term="geneology" /><category term="ancestors" /><category term="history" /><category term="research" /><category term="Charles Rennie Mackintosh" /><category term="Glasgow Art School" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those who know me well enough to communicate via email, know that I my personal domain that I use for email is glenelg. Very few, however, are aware of my reason for using this domain name. In this post, I hope to explain why (and it’s not just because it’s a very cool palindrome).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creating a Raspberry Pi Media Hub</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/20/full-featured-mediahub-pi4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating a Raspberry Pi Media Hub" /><published>2021-04-20T07:25:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-04-20T07:25:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/04/20/full-featured-mediahub-pi4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/20/full-featured-mediahub-pi4"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/rpihifi.jpg" alt="Raspberry Pi 4" />
<em>I’ve had a Raspberry Pi 3 hooked up to my HiFi for several years providing audio streaming support for the various mobile devices in our home. While it has also served as a Plex media server using a 2TB USB drive, it has never been powerful enough to support video playback at reasonable quality. When I got a Raspberry Pi4 with 8GB RAM recently, I decided it was time for an upgrade.</em>
<!--more--></p>

<p><strong>The Goal:</strong> To seamlessly replicate the existing Pi3 set-up as a Plex Media Server and Airplay. To add video and audio playback using the Pi4 as a media client.</p>

<p><strong>Stretch Goal:</strong> To support HiFi quality Tidal music streaming locally. I.e. without using a mobile device streaming over Airplay.</p>

<p><strong>Hardware:</strong> Raspberry Pi4 8GB, PiFi DAC+ 2.0 (This is a HiFi Berry clone), Argon NEO case, Rapoo K2800 Media Keyboard, Lexar S47 USB 256GB drive, Toshiba external 2TB drive.</p>

<p><strong>Software:</strong> Manjaro ARM MATE Desktop Community edition, Plex Media Server, Plex Media Player, shairport-sync.</p>

<p>I’m not going to detail the process of installing the operating system as there are many tutorials online that cover that process. However, I will say that I opted to install and boot off a USB drive rather than a Micro SD card because Micro SD cards are notoriously prone to corruption after sudden power loss whereas USB booted systems seem more stable. The availablity of fast USB3 drives means that they are also significanly faster than the internal MicroSD card reader as well.</p>

<p>I opted for <a href="https://manjaro.org/download/#raspberry-pi-4">Manjaro ARM edition</a> over Raspberry Pi OS, or Ubuntu because of the sheer scope of the Arch User Repository (The AUR). You could no doubt use PI OS or Ubuntu for this project, but you might have to get your hands dirty hunting around for 3rd party repositories or building from scratch. With the AUR, somebody has usually done the work for you and most apps have already been packaged for you. After flashing the Manjaro image to my USB drive on my main computer, I edited the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/boot/config.txt</code> file while it was still plugged into my laptop.</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c">#enable sound</span>
<span class="c">#dtparam=audio=on</span>
<span class="c"># Enable HiFiberry DAC Standard/Pro</span>
<span class="nv">dtoverlay</span><span class="o">=</span>hifiberry-dacplus
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dtparam</code> line is commented out to disable the internal Pi DAC and 3.5mm output because it’s not very good. The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dtoverlay</code> line enables support for hifiberry-dacplus DAC. Mine is a third part clone, but it’s compatible with the HiFi Berry so the settings work. This is about the only text editing that you have to do. The rest can be done within the MATE desktop on the Pi. Note, while editing the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">boot/config.txt</code> file, you could also overclock your Pi from 1.5MHz to 2GHz, but seriously, for this application you don’t need to and the Pi get’s warm enough as it is while rendering audio or video. Plus, with the DAC hat installed, you don’t have many cooling options.</p>]]></content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="Raspberry Pi" /><category term="Plex" /><category term="Plex Media Server" /><category term="Plex Media Player" /><category term="Manjaro" /><category term="Arm" /><category term="Arch Linux" /><category term="Tidal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve had a Raspberry Pi 3 hooked up to my HiFi for several years providing audio streaming support for the various mobile devices in our home. While it has also served as a Plex media server using a 2TB USB drive, it has never been powerful enough to support video playback at reasonable quality. When I got a Raspberry Pi4 with 8GB RAM recently, I decided it was time for an upgrade.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Arch is for Pros”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/07/arch-is-for-pros" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Arch is for Pros”" /><published>2021-04-07T08:01:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-04-07T08:01:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/04/07/arch-is-for-pros</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/07/arch-is-for-pros"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/arch.jpg" alt="Arch Linux Logo" />
<em>Recently, I’ve taken to scanning a selection of subreddits on reddit.com covering my interests in tech, photography etc. Today, on a Linux subreddit I saw the comment that titles this post, “Arch is for Pros”. The Arch, in this case is <a href="https://archlinux.org/">Arch Linux</a>, a notoriously tricky to setup Linux distro for those who like to live on the bleeding edge of technology (and Linux YouTubers). However, it got me thinking about the mis-appropriation and mis-use of the term “Pro”. Here are my thoughts on the matter.</em>
<!--more--></p>

<p>Many years ago I had a part-time job in a high-end HiFi equipment shop in Glasgow. We took pride in our approach, often lending equipment out to prospective customers to ensure that they found the right match for their musical appreciation.</p>

<p>Sometimes we would get customers in the shop, HiFi magazine in hand, demanding to hear (even to buy, unheard) the device reviewed in said magazine because it was labelled “Professional”, therefore it must be good. Our showroom manager would gently bring them down to earth by asking “Do you want a car or a truck? The vast majority of professional drivers are truck drivers and bus drivers, they drive professional vehicles. Trucks or buses. Would you buy a professional driver’s vehicle?”</p>

<p>Getting back to technology, the majority of professional use cases for Linux are in the running of servers: Database, Email, Web, etc. Whether they are running on-premise, in large managed datacenters or in “the cloud”, the two things that the professionals who run these servers value above all else are availability and security. It’s not uncommon to find servers on years-old operating systems and apps where only critical security patches have been applied.</p>

<p>I’ve been working in cloud computing since 2013. I wrote software that ran a daily security and configuration audit on over a thousand managed servers. Most of those servers were running CentOS or <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/amazon-linux-2/">Amazon Linux</a>, a significant minority were running Ubuntu. There may even have been a few running Debian, though I can’t remember ever coming across one. But one thing is certain, none were running Arch or Arch based distributions. Why is this? Put simply, Arch doesn’t support partial upgrades. There’s no way to just apply security patches. With Arch it’s all or nothing and, the longer you leave it, the higher the probability that something will break.</p>

<p>For a professional, it’s the stuff of nightmares.</p>

<p>I use an Arch distro as my daily driver (<a href="https://arcolinux.info">ArcoLinux</a>), does that make me un-professional? Perhaps. My laptop is not a mission-critical device. I like to tinker with it, installing things, tweaking things, breaking things. I know that I can completely re-install with a fresh OS and be back up and running in a couple of hours. However, that’s not a luxury afforded to the true professional Linux users.</p>

<p>I’m reminded again of something else my showroom manager back in the HiFi shop used to say: “I’m not an audiophile. Audiophiles like to listen to equipment. I like to listen to music”.</p>

<p>Maybe Arch is for audiophiles.</p>

<p>Enjoy the music.</p>]]></content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="arch" /><category term="linux" /><category term="professional" /><category term="reddit" /><category term="fan boys" /><category term="centos" /><category term="amazon linux" /><category term="aws" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="ArcoLinux" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently, I’ve taken to scanning a selection of subreddits on reddit.com covering my interests in tech, photography etc. Today, on a Linux subreddit I saw the comment that titles this post, “Arch is for Pros”. The Arch, in this case is Arch Linux, a notoriously tricky to setup Linux distro for those who like to live on the bleeding edge of technology (and Linux YouTubers). However, it got me thinking about the mis-appropriation and mis-use of the term “Pro”. Here are my thoughts on the matter.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Xiaomi Watch Color Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/03/23/xiaomi-watch-color" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Xiaomi Watch Color Review" /><published>2021-03-23T13:06:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-03-23T13:06:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/03/23/xiaomi-watch-color</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/03/23/xiaomi-watch-color"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/mwc-banner.jpg" alt="A selection of Xioami Watches" />
<em>I didn’t expect my Apple Watch Series 2 to last as long as it did. When I bought it over four years ago, I assumed that it would follow the usual route that mobile products follow. A couple of years of able performance followed by a steady decline in battery health until the off-charge life becomes too short. That would be the time to purchase a new one. Instead, the battery health only started to deteriorate a couple of months after I began working out for an hour each day last summer. By last month, it was time for a replacement. Read on to find out why I replaced it with a Xiaomi Watch Color and my thoughts on that watch.</em>
<!--more--></p>]]></content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="tech" /><category term="review" /><category term="smartwatches" /><category term="Xiaomi" /><category term="Apple" /><category term="Xiaomi watch color" /><category term="apple watch" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I didn’t expect my Apple Watch Series 2 to last as long as it did. When I bought it over four years ago, I assumed that it would follow the usual route that mobile products follow. A couple of years of able performance followed by a steady decline in battery health until the off-charge life becomes too short. That would be the time to purchase a new one. Instead, the battery health only started to deteriorate a couple of months after I began working out for an hour each day last summer. By last month, it was time for a replacement. Read on to find out why I replaced it with a Xiaomi Watch Color and my thoughts on that watch.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Taste of the Sea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/31/taste-of-the-sea" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Taste of the Sea" /><published>2020-12-31T13:51:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T13:51:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/31/taste-of-the-sea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/31/taste-of-the-sea"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/talisker1.jpg" alt="Talisker Bottle Banner" />
<em>“An intense Talisker, with a profoundly maritime character, like a warm welcome from a wild Hebridean sea”. So says the marketing spiel on the label on each bottle of Talisker Storm Single Malt Scotch Whisky. Colourful language, but do the contents deliver on the rather breathy description? Read on to find out.</em>
<!--more--></p>

<p><img src="/img/talisker2.jpg" alt="Talisker Bottle Banner" class="lft250" /></p>

<p>I don’t normally feel the urge to write reviews for whiskies. Unfortunately, I have a very poor sense of smell and, therefore, by extension, a poor sense of taste. I’m envious of people who can detect subtle hints of vanilla and forest fruits with refreshing lemon overtones and a delicate smokiness in anything. I rarely can.</p>

<p>This one, however, is different.</p>

<p>With the first gentle breath as my nose nears the glass, I’m taken back to childhood vacations on the North West coast of Scotland. Dried seaweed crunching underfoot at the high-tide line. Fishing in rockpools at low tide. The prickly machair on bare feet by the <a href="https://www.undiscoveredscotland.co.uk/lochinver/clachtoll/index.html">Bay of Clachtoll</a>.</p>

<p>My first sip takes me to the fishing harbour at Arbroath on Scotland’s East coast, near where my mother was born. The smell of the sea and the day’s catch fresh in my mind as my grand-parents indulge me in one more trip to the harbour to see the boats.</p>

<p>Another sip and, as the smooth liquid travels around my mouth, I’m transported to my teenage years in the Scouts sailing Wayfarer dinghies in Loch Goil with the salt spray in my face and the feel of salty rime from the unruly ropes as sixteen-year-old me gave younger scouts their first taste of sailing. Often cold. Often wet. Always fun.</p>

<p>I swallow a third sip and, as the slightly peppery tail recedes, I’m reminded of my early career as a navigation engineer on survey vessels, of the ubiquitous smell of salt and the sea that cakes every ship, of weathering North Sea storms in the warmth of my cabin as the sea swallowed my window in a green dim, before releasing it again for its next mouthful. A harsher life.</p>

<p>Perhaps I can’t name the subtle flavours of this dram, but I will remember it as it has reminded me. Maybe I too have been made by the sea.</p>]]></content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="whisky" /><category term="review" /><category term="memories" /><category term="nostalgia" /><category term="taliskerstorm" /><category term="talisker" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“An intense Talisker, with a profoundly maritime character, like a warm welcome from a wild Hebridean sea”. So says the marketing spiel on the label on each bottle of Talisker Storm Single Malt Scotch Whisky. Colourful language, but do the contents deliver on the rather breathy description? Read on to find out.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ONE LENS Challenge Gallery</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/12/one-lens-challenge-images" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ONE LENS Challenge Gallery" /><published>2020-11-12T08:09:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-11-12T08:09:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/12/one-lens-challenge-images</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/12/one-lens-challenge-images"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/ybax.jpg" alt="ONE LENS Challenge" />
<em>A gallery of images from my One Lens Challenge in November 2020. All images taken with Canon EOS-M5 with the 7Artisans 35mm f1.2 lens.</em>
<!--more--></p>
<div class="image-gallery">
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olc1.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olc1">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc1.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olc1" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olc2.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olc2">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc2.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olc2" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olc3.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olc3">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc3.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olc3" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olc4.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olc4">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc4.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olc4" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olc5.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olc5">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc5.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olc5" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olc6.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olc6">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc6.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olc6" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olc7.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olc7">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc7.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olc7" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olc8.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olc8">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc8.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olc8" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olc9.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olc9">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc9.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olc9" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olca.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olca">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olca.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olca" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olcb.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olcb">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olcb.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olcb" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olcc.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olcc">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olcc.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olcc" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        <a href="/img/one-lens/olcd.jpg" data-fancybox="gallery" title="olcd">
          <img src="//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olcd.jpg&amp;w=200&amp;h=200&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square" alt="olcd" />
        </a>
      
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
  </div>]]></content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="OneLensChallenge" /><category term="Canon" /><category term="EOS-M5" /><category term="7Artisans" /><category term="Manual Lens" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A gallery of images from my One Lens Challenge in November 2020. All images taken with Canon EOS-M5 with the 7Artisans 35mm f1.2 lens.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The ONE LENS Challenge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/03/one-lens-challenge" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The ONE LENS Challenge" /><published>2020-11-03T19:06:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-11-03T19:06:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/03/one-lens-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/03/one-lens-challenge"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/lens.jpg" alt="EOS-M5 7Artisans 35mm f1.2" /></p>

<p><em>A few days ago, I watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bKMaEAxPskU">this post on YouTube</a>. It seemed like a fun idea so I decided to give it a try. (If you didn’t have time to watch the video, the assignment is to use a single prime lens for all of your personal photography for the month of November.)</em>
<!--more--></p>

<p>So, I had to decide which lens to use on my Canon EOS-M5. I have five prime lenses at present. In order of focal length they are:</p>

<p><strong>7 Artisans 7.5mm f2.8 Fisheye</strong>: This as a very distinctive lens. With its 7.5mm focal length (12mm in full-frame terms) it is, by far, the widest lens that I’ve ever owned. In the right situation, it gives a great perspective, but, hmmm, not for everyday use.</p>

<p><strong>Canon EF-M 22mm f2.0</strong>: This highly regarded prime lens is light, unobtrusive, and, with its 35mm equivalent focal length would seem the ideal choice for city life and the inevitable street photography shots. But, it’s a bit boring, not a challenge.</p>

<p><strong>Sigma 30mm f1.4</strong>: This is a lovely lens. It’s fast, it’s sharp, at 48mm equivalent focal length it harks back to the days when I first started photography when every camera was bundled with a 50mm f1.8 “standard” lens. I love this lens and it was my first choice for this challenge. But, yeah, it’s too easy to go for the first choice, where’s the challenge?</p>

<p><strong>7 Artisans 35mm f1.2</strong>: This is, by far, the cutest lens that I have. The retro styling of this <a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Zeiss_Sonnar">Sonnar</a> inspired design looks great on any camera. It has zero electronics, just purely manual focus and aperture. However, there are situations where it suffers from a weird vignette. It looks great, but it’s a flawed beauty (and, of course, has to be manually focused, just like the old days).</p>

<p><strong>Canon EF 50mm f1.5 (nifty fifty)</strong> This is my only EF prime lens. I use it with an adaptor on my EF-M mount. At the moment, its 80mm equivalent focal length is probably my favorite. Whenever I head out with this lens on my camera, I never fail to come back with some satisfying images. It would seem that this lens is a good candidate for this challenge. But there we go again, where’s the challenge?</p>

<p>So, I’ve decided, if you haven’t already worked it out, to go with the flawed but cute 7 Artisans 35mm f1.2. It’s a manual focus lens. I hope that that will force me to take some more time to “get it right”, to think more about composition and the basics of photography. To get away from the “running and gunning” method that quick autofocus and seemingly unlimited storage encourages. In keeping with the retro nature of the lens, I’ve decide to try (no promises) and stick to black and white images for the duration.</p>

<p>Of course, I need to get out and shoot. I’ve taken my first two photos already, in and around the apartment (itchy finger syndrome). Here they are. I’ll post subsequent images here and on the usual culprits (Flickr and Twitter)</p>

<p><img src="/img/starbucks.jpg" alt="Selection of Starbucks nespresson pods" style="width: 480px;" /><br />
<img src="/img/cys.jpg" alt="Focused on Homework" style="width: 480px;" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="OneLensChallenge" /><category term="Canon" /><category term="EOS-M5" /><category term="7Artisans" /><category term="Manual Lens" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days ago, I watched this post on YouTube. It seemed like a fun idea so I decided to give it a try. (If you didn’t have time to watch the video, the assignment is to use a single prime lens for all of your personal photography for the month of November.)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Simple Common Sense</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/02/simple-common-sense" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Simple Common Sense" /><published>2020-11-02T11:43:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-11-02T11:43:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/02/simple-common-sense</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/02/simple-common-sense"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://twitter.com/bopinion/status/1322937610348777474"><img src="/img/graph.jpg" alt="Graph of Covid deaths per million by country" style="width: 582px;" /></a></p>

<p>The above tweet was recently posted by <a href="https://twitter.com/bopinion/">Bloomberg Opinion</a>. I was aware that East Asian nations had been significantly more successful in dealing with the Covid19 pandemic, but I hadn’t realized the magnitude of the difference.</p>]]></content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="covid19" /><category term="masks" /><category term="virus" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The above tweet was recently posted by Bloomberg Opinion. I was aware that East Asian nations had been significantly more successful in dealing with the Covid19 pandemic, but I hadn’t realized the magnitude of the difference.]]></summary></entry></feed>