<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-19T15:10:33+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">TramFishers</title><subtitle>Tramfishers.com, a site set aside for writing, sharing, grumbling and (maybe) ranting. I&apos;m Fraser Smith, a freelance developer and amateur photographer living in Shanghai. Why TramFishers? Let&apos;s just say that it has me very confused. SmarterFish was already taken and I didn&apos;t really fancy ShitFarmers (it&apos;s an anagram).
</subtitle><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><entry><title type="html">“Arch is for Pros”</title><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/2021/04/07/arch-is-for-pros" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Arch is for Pros”" /><published>2021-04-07T08:01:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-04-07T08:01:00+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/2021/04/07/arch-is-for-pros</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.tramfishers.com/2021/04/07/arch-is-for-pros">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/arch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arch Linux Logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Recently, I’ve taken to scanning a selection of subreddits on reddit.com covering my interests in tech, photography etc. Today, on a Linux subreddit I saw the comment that titles this post, “Arch is for Pros”. The Arch, in this case is &lt;a href=&quot;https://archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;, a notoriously tricky to setup Linux distro for those who like to live on the bleeding edge of technology (and Linux YouTubers). However, it got me thinking about the mis-appropriation and mis-use of the term “Pro”. Here are my thoughts on the matter.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years ago I had a part-time job in a high-end HiFi equipment shop in Glasgow. We took pride in our approach, often lending equipment out to prospective customers to ensure that they found the right match for their musical appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we would get customers in the shop, HiFi magazine in hand, demanding to hear (even to buy, unheard) the device reviewed in said magazine because it was labelled “Professional”, therefore it must be good. Our showroom manager would gently bring them down to earth by asking “Do you want a car or a truck? The vast majority of professional drivers are truck drivers and bus drivers, they drive professional vehicles. Trucks or buses. Would you buy a professional driver’s vehicle?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting back to technology, the majority of professional use cases for Linux are in the running of servers: Database, Email, Web, etc. Whether they are running on-premise, in large managed datacenters or in “the cloud”, the two things that the professionals who run these servers value above all else are availability and security. It’s not uncommon to find servers on years-old operating systems and apps where only critical security patches have been applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working in cloud computing since 2013. I wrote software that ran a daily security and configuration audit on over a thousand managed servers. Most of those servers were running CentOS or &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/amazon-linux-2/&quot;&gt;Amazon Linux&lt;/a&gt;, a significant minority were running Ubuntu. There may even have been a few running Debian, though I can’t remember ever coming across one. But one thing is certain, none were running Arch or Arch based distributions. Why is this? Put simply, Arch doesn’t support partial upgrades. There’s no way to just apply security patches. With Arch it’s all or nothing and, the longer you leave it, the higher the probability that something will break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a professional, it’s the stuff of nightmares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use an Arch distro as my daily driver (&lt;a href=&quot;https://arcolinux.info&quot;&gt;ArcoLinux&lt;/a&gt;), does that make me un-professional? Perhaps. My laptop is not a mission-critical device. I like to tinker with it, installing things, tweaking things, breaking things. I know that I can completely re-install with a fresh OS and be back up and running in a couple of hours. However, that’s not a luxury afforded to the true professional Linux users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m reminded again of something else my showroom manager back in the HiFi shop used to say: “I’m not an audiophile. Audiophiles like to listen to equipment. I like to listen to music”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe Arch is for audiophiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the music.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="arch" /><category term="linux" /><category term="professional" /><category term="reddit" /><category term="fan boys" /><category term="centos" /><category term="amazon linux" /><category term="aws" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="ArcoLinux" /><summary type="html">Recently, I’ve taken to scanning a selection of subreddits on reddit.com covering my interests in tech, photography etc. Today, on a Linux subreddit I saw the comment that titles this post, “Arch is for Pros”. The Arch, in this case is Arch Linux, a notoriously tricky to setup Linux distro for those who like to live on the bleeding edge of technology (and Linux YouTubers). However, it got me thinking about the mis-appropriation and mis-use of the term “Pro”. Here are my thoughts on the matter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Taste of the Sea</title><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/12/31/taste-of-the-sea" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Taste of the Sea" /><published>2020-12-31T13:51:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T13:51:00+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/12/31/taste-of-the-sea</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/12/31/taste-of-the-sea">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/talisker1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Talisker Bottle Banner&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“An intense Talisker, with a profoundly maritime character, like a warm welcome from a wild Hebridean sea”. So says the marketing spiel on the label on each bottle of Talisker Storm Single Malt Scotch Whisky. Colourful language, but do the contents deliver on the rather breathy description? Read on to find out.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/talisker2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Talisker Bottle Banner&quot; class=&quot;lft250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t normally feel the urge to write reviews for whiskies. Unfortunately, I have a very poor sense of smell and, therefore, by extension, a poor sense of taste. I’m envious of people who can detect subtle hints of vanilla and forest fruits with refreshing lemon overtones and a delicate smokiness in anything. I rarely can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one, however, is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the first gentle breath as my nose nears the glass, I’m taken back to childhood vacations on the North West coast of Scotland. Dried seaweed crunching underfoot at the high-tide line. Fishing in rockpools at low tide. The prickly machair on bare feet by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.undiscoveredscotland.co.uk/lochinver/clachtoll/index.html&quot;&gt;Bay of Clachtoll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first sip takes me to the fishing harbour at Arbroath on Scotland’s East coast, near where my mother was born. The smell of the sea and the day’s catch fresh in my mind as my grand-parents indulge me in one more trip to the harbour to see the boats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another sip and, as the smooth liquid travels around my mouth, I’m transported to my teenage years in the Scouts sailing Wayfarer dinghies in Loch Goil with the salt spray in my face and the feel of salty rime from the unruly ropes as sixteen-year-old me gave younger scouts their first taste of sailing. Often cold. Often wet. Always fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swallow a third sip and, as the slightly peppery tail recedes, I’m reminded of my early career as a navigation engineer on survey vessels, of the ubiquitous smell of salt and the sea that cakes every ship, of weathering North Sea storms in the warmth of my cabin as the sea swallowed my window in a green dim, before releasing it again for its next mouthful. A harsher life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I can’t name the subtle flavours of this dram, but I will remember it as it has reminded me. Maybe I too have been made by the sea.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="whisky" /><category term="review" /><category term="memories" /><category term="nostalgia" /><category term="taliskerstorm" /><category term="talisker" /><summary type="html">“An intense Talisker, with a profoundly maritime character, like a warm welcome from a wild Hebridean sea”. So says the marketing spiel on the label on each bottle of Talisker Storm Single Malt Scotch Whisky. Colourful language, but do the contents deliver on the rather breathy description? Read on to find out.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ONE LENS Challenge Gallery</title><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/11/12/one-lens-challenge-images" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ONE LENS Challenge Gallery" /><published>2020-11-12T08:09:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-11-12T08:09:00+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/11/12/one-lens-challenge-images</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/11/12/one-lens-challenge-images">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ybax.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ONE LENS Challenge&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A gallery of images from my One Lens Challenge in November 2020. All images taken with Canon EOS-M5 with the 7Artisans 35mm f1.2 lens.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olc1.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olc1&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc1.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olc1&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olc2.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olc2&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc2.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olc2&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olc3.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olc3&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc3.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olc3&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olc4.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olc4&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc4.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olc4&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olc5.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olc5&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc5.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olc5&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olc6.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olc6&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc6.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olc6&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olc7.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olc7&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc7.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olc7&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olc8.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olc8&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc8.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olc8&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olc9.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olc9&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olc9.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olc9&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olca.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olca&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olca.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olca&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olcb.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olcb&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olcb.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olcb&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olcc.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olcc&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olcc.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olcc&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
      

        
        
        &lt;a href=&quot;/img/one-lens/olcd.jpg&quot; data-fancybox=&quot;gallery&quot; title=&quot;olcd&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=tramfishers.com/img/one-lens/olcd.jpg&amp;amp;w=200&amp;amp;h=200&amp;amp;output=jpg&amp;amp;q=50&amp;amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;olcd&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
    
  
  &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="OneLensChallenge" /><category term="Canon" /><category term="EOS-M5" /><category term="7Artisans" /><category term="Manual Lens" /><summary type="html">A gallery of images from my One Lens Challenge in November 2020. All images taken with Canon EOS-M5 with the 7Artisans 35mm f1.2 lens.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The ONE LENS Challenge</title><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/11/03/one-lens-challenge" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The ONE LENS Challenge" /><published>2020-11-03T19:06:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-11-03T19:06:00+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/11/03/one-lens-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/11/03/one-lens-challenge">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/lens.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EOS-M5 7Artisans 35mm f1.2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A few days ago, I watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bKMaEAxPskU&quot;&gt;this post on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. It seemed like a fun idea so I decided to give it a try. (If you didn’t have time to watch the video, the assignment is to use a single prime lens for all of your personal photography for the month of November.)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I had to decide which lens to use on my Canon EOS-M5. I have five prime lenses at present. In order of focal length they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7 Artisans 7.5mm f2.8 Fisheye&lt;/strong&gt;: This as a very distinctive lens. With its 7.5mm focal length (12mm in full-frame terms) it is, by far, the widest lens that I’ve ever owned. In the right situation, it gives a great perspective, but, hmmm, not for everyday use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canon EF-M 22mm f2.0&lt;/strong&gt;: This highly regarded prime lens is light, unobtrusive, and, with its 35mm equivalent focal length would seem the ideal choice for city life and the inevitable street photography shots. But, it’s a bit boring, not a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sigma 30mm f1.4&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a lovely lens. It’s fast, it’s sharp, at 48mm equivalent focal length it harks back to the days when I first started photography when every camera was bundled with a 50mm f1.8 “standard” lens. I love this lens and it was my first choice for this challenge. But, yeah, it’s too easy to go for the first choice, where’s the challenge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7 Artisans 35mm f1.2&lt;/strong&gt;: This is, by far, the cutest lens that I have. The retro styling of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Zeiss_Sonnar&quot;&gt;Sonnar&lt;/a&gt; inspired design looks great on any camera. It has zero electronics, just purely manual focus and aperture. However, there are situations where it suffers from a weird vignette. It looks great, but it’s a flawed beauty (and, of course, has to be manually focused, just like the old days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canon EF 50mm f1.5 (nifty fifty)&lt;/strong&gt; This is my only EF prime lens. I use it with an adaptor on my EF-M mount. At the moment, its 80mm equivalent focal length is probably my favorite. Whenever I head out with this lens on my camera, I never fail to come back with some satisfying images. It would seem that this lens is a good candidate for this challenge. But there we go again, where’s the challenge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve decided, if you haven’t already worked it out, to go with the flawed but cute 7 Artisans 35mm f1.2. It’s a manual focus lens. I hope that that will force me to take some more time to “get it right”, to think more about composition and the basics of photography. To get away from the “running and gunning” method that quick autofocus and seemingly unlimited storage encourages. In keeping with the retro nature of the lens, I’ve decide to try (no promises) and stick to black and white images for the duration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I need to get out and shoot. I’ve taken my first two photos already, in and around the apartment (itchy finger syndrome). Here they are. I’ll post subsequent images here and on the usual culprits (Flickr and Twitter)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/starbucks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Selection of Starbucks nespresson pods&quot; style=&quot;width: 480px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/cys.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Focused on Homework&quot; style=&quot;width: 480px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="OneLensChallenge" /><category term="Canon" /><category term="EOS-M5" /><category term="7Artisans" /><category term="Manual Lens" /><summary type="html">A few days ago, I watched this post on YouTube. It seemed like a fun idea so I decided to give it a try. (If you didn’t have time to watch the video, the assignment is to use a single prime lens for all of your personal photography for the month of November.)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Camera Life 6</title><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/08/13/photographing-lightning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camera Life 6" /><published>2020-08-13T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-08-13T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/08/13/photographing-lightning</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/08/13/photographing-lightning">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/lightning-banner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lightning Flashes Across The Sky&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have been following my sporadic posts about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tramfishers.com/2019/10/17/a-life-in-cameras-1&quot;&gt;Camera Life&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll be aware that I’ve been a camera owner (and therefore a hobbyist photographer) for over fifty years. In that time, I have only managed to photograph lightning successfully twice. Each time I used a different technique and each time I succeeded… eventually.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first thirty years of my photography hobby I shot with 35mm film. Even trying to photograph lightning would be a very wasteful and costly endeavor. Living in the UK didn’t help, lightning just isn’t that common. Later, when I started traveling and spending more time in the tropics I did see more storms, but I was usually working offshore so trying to photograph lightning could easily have used up my whole trip’s film supply with no hope of replenishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until the advent of digital photography in the late twentieth century that photographing lightning became feasible. Even then it took another ten years or so before the right combination of location, climate, and vantage point enabled my first attempt at capturing lightning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;page-subtitle&quot;&gt;First Attempt, August 2010&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/lightning2010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lightning Flashes Across The Sky, August 2010&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, we moved to Shanghai. Our apartment, on the twentieth floor, has a good view south towards the Huangpu River. I was using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dpreview.com/products/ricoh/compacts/ricoh_grdigital3&quot;&gt;Ricoh GRDIII&lt;/a&gt; camera at this time. The little Ricoh certainly wasn’t the ideal camera for this challenge. However, it did have some redeeming features that made capturing the shot easier, if not predictable. After a few failed attempts trying to time my shutter presses with flashes of lightning, I resorted to automation. The Ricoh had a very flexible manual focusing system for a compact camera so I was able to manually focus on infinity and disable the inevitable hunting for focus that would result from trying to use autofocus. I then configured the built-in interval timer to take one shot every five seconds. I walked away and left it on a table-top tripod shooting. I can’t remember whether the SD card filled up or the battery ran out first. However, by the time it stopped shooting, the storm was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On loading several hundred shots into my computer, I had the one keeper and several near misses. I’ve reprocessed the original raw file with my current iPad Pro workflow and I’m pleased to see that it looks even better now than it did ten years ago. Not bad for a ten-megapixel compact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technique: Manually focus on infinity, interval shooting at five seconds, hope that you get lucky.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;page-subtitle&quot;&gt;Second Attempt, August 2020&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.picfair.com/pics/011819435-lightning-over-shanghai&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/lightning2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lightning Flashes Across The Sky, August 2020&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to this year, almost exactly ten years after the first image. Of course there have been many thunderstorms in the intervening years, but none seem to have coincided with me being here to shoot, night-time, and being visible from the southern side of our building. I’m now using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dpreview.com/products/canon/slrs/canon_eosm5&quot;&gt;Canon EOS-M5&lt;/a&gt; mirrorless camera. The M5 is a much more capable camera, especially when paired with the 11-22mm wide-angle zoom. However, it doesn’t support interval shooting so the lazy option I used before wasn’t available this time (I could have used the Canon EOS app to set this up, but it’s not something I use often so I didn’t want to waste time). Instead, the M5 has a reasonably fast multiple shot burst rate of about nine frames per second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that there is often a short pre-flash with some lightning bolts. By setting the lens to manual focus on infinity, again, to eliminate autofocus hunting, I was often able to press and hold the shutter when I first saw a flash and then shoot a burst over the next second or two capturing any subsequent forks of lightning. With a bit of practice, this method was more successful than the previous method and resulted in more successful captures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image above is a composite of two consecutive images about 100ms apart. The first caught the start of the fork as the bolt of lightning shot down from the top left. The second caught the caught multiple branches seeking an earth point. I stacked these two images in Affinity Photo on my iPad Pro and then finished the processing in Pixelmator Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technique: Manually focus on infinity, set the camera to burst shooting, and press and hold the shutter down when you think there’s going to be a fork.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither of these methods is particularly reliable. You will end up with hundreds of exposures of dark skies or glowing clouds. You will also miss some beauties and capture some boring strikes. Such is life. However, if you persevere you can get results.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="tutorial, photography" /><category term="writing" /><category term="write52" /><category term="tutorial" /><category term="photography" /><category term="weather" /><category term="storm" /><category term="lightning" /><summary type="html">If you have been following my sporadic posts about Camera Life, you’ll be aware that I’ve been a camera owner (and therefore a hobbyist photographer) for over fifty years. In that time, I have only managed to photograph lightning successfully twice. Each time I used a different technique and each time I succeeded… eventually.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Time for a Break</title><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/04/22/taking-a-break" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time for a Break" /><published>2020-04-22T18:33:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-22T18:33:00+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/04/22/taking-a-break</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/04/22/taking-a-break">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Random people sitting on a bench&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I’d never join a club that would allow a person like me to become a member.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;― Groucho Marx&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About fifteen years ago, I discovered that I enjoyed writing. I think I discovered it most when a popular blog shared one of my posts, and I experienced the frisson of a post gaining ten thousand views in twelve hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years later, I had relocated to Shanghai and had an educational startup. I was writing weekly blog posts for this company and enjoying the process. Late in 2010, a twitter friend, (hi &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zee&quot;&gt;@zee&lt;/a&gt;), posted that his company was looking for somebody in Asia to write about tech subjects from Asia. I jumped at the opportunity. While I had worked in the publishing industry for thirteen years, it was in a technical role. I wasn’t a trained journalist. But I enjoyed writing. I felt I could do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenextweb.com&quot;&gt;TNW&lt;/a&gt; in the autumn of 2010 as its “Asia Editor”. How cool is that? An editor. Me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part, in the beginning, I suffered from imposter syndrome, &lt;em&gt;I wasn’t a real writer&lt;/em&gt;. Luckily the team was great and helped the new boy out. However, what I couldn’t get used to was the writing to order. I was expected to publish at least three stories a day, five days a week. The stories didn’t have to be too long but I found the pressure incredible. Especially on Mondays. Tech news usually moves to US West coast time. On Mondays in Asia, not much tech stuff happens until, well, Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other problem was that, before TNW, I wrote about things that interest me. I still do. Working for TNW, there were times when a story came up that had to be written and published within fifteen minutes (to beat &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com&quot;&gt;Techcrunch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com&quot;&gt;Mashable&lt;/a&gt;). Even if the subject matter was of little interest to the average techie (or me), the scoop was the goal, not the subject. I struggled with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months later I was relieved when TNW sacked me (Thanks @zee!). It is the only time in my career that I’ve been sacked and I never expected to feel so happy about it. But I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to the present. I still like writing, on my terms, about subjects that interest me. I’ve been meaning to get back into it more regularly so, last year, I started this site, tramfishers.com (yes, it’s a stupid name, I know. Too late now.), to focus more on written pieces as opposed to the photos that I usually post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, a friend started posting with the #Write52 hashtag. I investigated and found the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.write52.com/&quot;&gt;Write52&lt;/a&gt; project where people try to write and publish one post per week. It sounded like fun. This also coincided with the first weeks of lockdown in China so I also had something to write about. Three months later, and it’s not so much fun anymore. I missed last week completely, despite having three good ideas for posts. The previous week, my whole post was a haiku. The problem is that the drive to come up with something every week has become a chore. It’s no longer fun. So, I’ve decided that this will be my final regular #Write52 post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I going to stop writing? No, after all, I’ve still got three good ideas to write about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s just that I’ll be writing on my terms when I want to. No pressure. Maybe I’ll even tag some future posts as #Write52 in the cheeky hope that I might garner a few views from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="write52" /><category term="tnw" /><category term="TheNextWeb" /><summary type="html">“I’d never join a club that would allow a person like me to become a member.” ― Groucho Marx</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Springtime Haiku</title><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/04/09/springtime" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Springtime Haiku" /><published>2020-04-09T13:40:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-09T13:40:00+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/04/09/springtime</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/04/09/springtime">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tree-pollen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tree pollen&quot; /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Shanghai in springtime. &lt;br /&gt;
Tree pollen falling like snow. &lt;br /&gt;
Unseen in winter. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="haiku" /><category term="poetry" /><category term="seasons" /><category term="spring" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Camera Life 5</title><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/04/02/camera-life-5" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camera Life 5" /><published>2020-04-02T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-02T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/04/02/camera-life-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/04/02/camera-life-5">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/terragen2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Landscape with Terragen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s hard to believe that a hobby program from a student at York University would be the catalyst to get me back into photography, but that’s exactly what happened in the late nineties. I cannot deny that, photographically, I’d lost my way at that time. In career terms, things were going well, I had left the offshore life in 1994 after a year posted to China and started working in the newspaper industry as an advertising systems engineer. On the personal front, however, it was pretty awful. And that is all that I’m going to say on that subject. It’s water under the bridge.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as long as I had owned computers (about fifteen years or so at this time) I had been interested in using those machines to create photo-realistic rendered images. I was a fan of the work of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Ken_Musgrave&quot;&gt;Ken Musgrave&lt;/a&gt;, a pioneer in the field. The Acorn Archimedes that I bought in 1987 was probably my first computer that could produce realistic images in a practical timeframe. One of my favorite programs on this machine was a BBC basic program called “Magrathea” that, you’ve guessed it, created computer-generated landscapes. It was fun hacking the program to improve the realism of the output, but it couldn’t be called photo realistic in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward about a decade and the world is a different place. Windows 95 is already the dominant operating system and boring beige boxes ruled the roost. I was still into 3D rendering, but, at my level, there was still no realistic landscape generating application at the hobbyist end of the market. It’s at this point that I heard about a beta app created by a student programmer at York University called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/name/nm1232297/&quot;&gt;Matt Fairclough&lt;/a&gt;, his app was called &lt;a href=&quot;https://planetside.co.uk&quot;&gt;Terragen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s this got to do with photography? Bear with me and you’ll find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terragen was everything that I had been looking for. It allowed me to create photo-realistic landscapes (within certain boundaries) on my Windows PC, and it did it well. Not only that but, it also had a very vibrant user community for sharing and discussing creations. I made friends on the Terragen group that remain friends to this day. However, all was not well. When creating my imaginary landscapes, I would often spend hours tweaking viewpoints and compositions to achieve the best possible image. I noticed, at this time, that not everyone took the same care. For many people, the composition took second place to the photo-realistic aspects of their images. Many images looked great but didn’t work as anything but technical demonstrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that my problem was that I was trying to create works that were realistic but also compositionally attractive too. I was trying to render landscape photos. Everywhere I went, I started looking at the landscape with a new eye, an eye to how I would render it. This soon led to me thinking about how I might photograph the landscape. It was time to get back into photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1998, I bought one of the first digital cameras on the market. A Fujifilm DX-7. This was an expensive plastic thing that shot at 640x480 VGA resolution. I have no surviving photos from this camera and my only memory of it is when it seized up from the cold on the summit of Mount Washington in New Hampshire. However, I had the digital bug and soon replaced it with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dpreview.com/reviews/olympusc2500l/&quot;&gt;Olympus C2500L&lt;/a&gt; a much better machine with a massive 2.5-megapixel sensor and a zoom lens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2000, my company wanted to send me to Hong Kong. However, before I could go to Hong Kong, I would have to visit the head office in Boston for some training first. I wasn’t so keen on the idea of flying from London to Boston on a Tuesday, returning to London on Friday and then leaving for Hong Kong on Sunday. So, I suggested that on Friday, I fly to Seattle instead and then onwards to Hong Kong on the following Monday. The company agreed. This would give me a weekend in Washington and a chance to meet up with Terragen friends Tim and Angela O’Donoghue. The first &lt;a href=&quot;http://timster.net/angela//mt-st-helens/index.htm&quot;&gt;Terragen Intercontinental Conference&lt;/a&gt; was born. It was great to discover that Tim also had a C2500L (He reminded me to mention that yesterday).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visit was a success, we went to Mount St. Helens, its landscape still showing signs of devastation twenty years after the eruption. On the second day, Tim and I headed north into the Cascades to photograph the awesome Mount Shuksan and to experience the surreal novelty (for me) of fifteen-foot deep snow-drifts, on a hot sunny July day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second Terragen Intercontinental Conference took place a year later in Los Angeles and coincided with SIGGRAPH2001. This one was truly intercontinental with attendees from the UK, the USA, and New Zealand. Matt (living in LA by this time) was there as was Terragen’s Macintosh coder, Jo, from New Zealand, and Ken Musgrave who was promoting his new product, “Mojoworld” that year. Tim and I still managed to grab a day off From the hectic foot pounding schedule of the exhibition halls and head out to Joshua Tree National Park with our C2500Ls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-1&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-2&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-3&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-4&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-5&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-6&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="cameras" /><category term="photography" /><category term="gas" /><category term="autobiographical" /><category term="Olympus C2500L" /><category term="Olympus" /><category term="Seattle" /><category term="Washington" /><category term="Terragen" /><category term="software" /><summary type="html">It’s hard to believe that a hobby program from a student at York University would be the catalyst to get me back into photography, but that’s exactly what happened in the late nineties. I cannot deny that, photographically, I’d lost my way at that time. In career terms, things were going well, I had left the offshore life in 1994 after a year posted to China and started working in the newspaper industry as an advertising systems engineer. On the personal front, however, it was pretty awful. And that is all that I’m going to say on that subject. It’s water under the bridge.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.tramfishers.com/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/terragen.jpg%22%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.tramfishers.com/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/terragen.jpg%22%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Life Under Lockdown 6</title><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/03/25/life-under-lockdown-6" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Under Lockdown 6" /><published>2020-03-25T18:30:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T18:30:00+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/03/25/life-under-lockdown-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/03/25/life-under-lockdown-6">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/empty-road2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An empty road in Shanghai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With most of the world seemingly under lockdown now, I didn’t think there was much scope for another “Life Under Lockdown” post. I was even toying with the idea of a new series, “life After Lockdown” based on the improvements to our situation here in Shanghai. However, events of the last weekend served as a reminder that, even if we’re not totally under lockdown, China is, and it’s getting stricter.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, we’ve been able to get out more for non-essential trips. My wife was on one such trip last Friday. As she returned home, I could see from the app on my phone that the car was parked downstairs, but she didn’t get home for another 40 minutes. When she eventually returned, she explained that there had been an emergency residents’ committee meeting. The son of one of our neighbors would be returning from his studies at a European university the following Sunday so plans had to be formulated for his quarantine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These plans would require the adding of additional surveillance to his parents’ apartment to trigger an alarm with the local police if there was any unauthorized departure. They were taking this seriously. They also decided that one of the building’s two elevators would be off for several hours each day to allow for the collection of household waste and subsequent disinfection of the elevator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday came and, with it, the news that the student would be detained at the airport for 24 hours until his virus check was completed. With so many 10-15 minute tests hitting the market, it seems that the authorities are still using the older, slower tests. Maybe they’re still more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday passed without incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday morning, the excitement started to build. Not only was the famous student returning home, but he would also do so in style. In an ambulance (not so stylish I’ll grant you) with a police escort. As 11:45 drew close everyone was at their windows to see the show, phones at the ready to record the events for posterity. We later found out that the local party chief was in attendance, as were two videographers, to ensure that everything was handled properly and securely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on Monday, the Shanghai government announced that as from March 25th, all arrivals at the airports would be automatically quarantined at government facilities (converted sports halls, I think) for 14 days. I guess that’ll free up the ambulances, police and party chiefs for more important duties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best and take care!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="covid-19" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">With most of the world seemingly under lockdown now, I didn’t think there was much scope for another “Life Under Lockdown” post. I was even toying with the idea of a new series, “life After Lockdown” based on the improvements to our situation here in Shanghai. However, events of the last weekend served as a reminder that, even if we’re not totally under lockdown, China is, and it’s getting stricter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Camera Life 4</title><link href="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/03/18/camera-life-4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camera Life 4" /><published>2020-03-18T18:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-18T18:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/03/18/camera-life-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/03/18/camera-life-4">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/cameras/oly-bw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Olympus XA Camera plus film&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nothing could have prepared me for the intense heat and humidity of Houston, Texas, in the late summer of 1984, when I arrived there for my first overseas posting. Even the TV weather forecasts couldn’t cope when screen weather tickers topped out at 99% humidity for the simple reason that they couldn’t handle the three digits required to display 100%.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduating from college in 1983, I spent the summer months working in a Hi-fi shop in Glasgow while I looked for a full-time job. I found that job in the autumn and started my training a few weeks before Christmas. Very early on, I learned that the job would entail a lot of overseas travel and that I would be spending a lot of time at sea. It seemed that traveling light would be the order of the day and I wouldn’t be able to take my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/03/11/a-life-in-cameras-3&quot;&gt;SLR and lenses&lt;/a&gt; with me on my trips. A smaller camera was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My 21st birthday was in February 1984, so I asked my sister and brother-in-law for a new camera as a birthday gift. The camera that I chose was the very compact and entirely pocketable Olympus XA. I could write hundreds of words about this camera but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.casualphotophile.com/2018/06/20/olympus-xa-review-35mm-film-camera-rangefinder/&quot;&gt;Casual Photo File&lt;/a&gt; does a much better job than I could and I’m not trying to write about cameras per se.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The XA became my carry-everywhere camera for the next fifteen years or so. Right up until I bought my first digital camera in the late nineties. Even since that time I have still run the occasional roll of film through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job was with a company called Racal Survey, although, in many parts of the world, it was still known by its more historically famous name Decca Survey. As an aside Decca Survey was a separate company from Decca Records, the company that infamously rejected The Beatles. Decca Survey was more famous as the company built out of the technological advances in navigation made during World War Two that enabled the thousand bomber raids over Germany by using its accurate (for the time) navigation network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several training courses in the UK and a couple of offshore jobs in the North Sea, I was ready for my first overseas posting, Houston, Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steamy as Houston was, it was nothing compared to the location for my first assignment of that trip. After a week in the office acclimatizing, I was given a pickup truck and sent to look after a system monitoring station on the gulf coast of Louisiana. &lt;img src=&quot;/img/fs-houston.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FS in Houston, 1984&quot; class=&quot;lft&quot; /&gt;The station itself consisted of a 10 m antenna erected at the edge of a small trailer park some ten miles off the main road and a mile or two from the coast. The monitoring equipment was housed in one of the trailers. It turned out that this was where I too was to be housed for the next three weeks. Whoa, three years of study and, a year after graduation, I’m living in a trailer park in rural Louisiana. That was unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life in the trailer park was “interesting”. I soon learned to be careful when putting the trash out as some small black slithery, almost certainly venomous, wildlife liked to hide in the shade under the bin. I was glad to see that they were just as worried about me as I was about them as they disappeared with some speed when exposed. &lt;img src=&quot;/img/gulf-sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset on the Gulf of Mexico 1984&quot; class=&quot;rght&quot; /&gt; Every evening in the dusk, I was entertained by a light show from thousands of fireflies at the edge of the nearby wood. My neighbors told me that there were alligators in the area too although I never managed to see any, even after making a couple of special trips to the places where they were supposed to hang out. I did see a few later in the trip when I had to over-fly the region in a helicopter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also entertained by my trailer park neighbor, Lionel (“Lah’own’eyll”) and his timid wife, Dolly. In the politically incorrect words (even then) of my Texan colleagues, Lionel was a “coon-ass”, the Louisiana equivalent of a “red-neck” in Texas. Basically, he was poor, white, and rural. He was a big man, best described as the human equivalent in stature and speech of &lt;a href=&quot;https://looneytunes.fandom.com/wiki/Foghorn_Leghorn&quot;&gt;Foghorn Leghorn&lt;/a&gt; the Looney Tunes cartoon rooster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lionel, it turned out, liked to do odd jobs and, according to Lionel, my predecessors always paid him $20 to cut the grass around the antenna. I’m not sure if that was entirely true, but I was happy enough to give him the work because it was a large area and the days were hot. This paid off as Lionel then offered to introduce me to the local speciality, gumbo, “dat’s good eat’n boy, good eat’n” is how I remember him describing it to me. What he omitted to explain was that he was going to cook this crab gumbo (an all-day affair) in my trailer, on my stove, using my gas. I think I ended up paying for the crabs as well. No matter, it was good eat’n.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have several more stories from this period maybe I’ll revisit it in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my last &lt;em&gt;successful&lt;/em&gt; outing with the Olympus XA was almost twenty years later in the Netherlands. Long after leaving Racal, I was working on a publishing project in Amsterdam. A dutch friend invited me to join her on a peculiarly dutch activity called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wadlopen.net/&quot;&gt;wadlopen&lt;/a&gt;. On certain days (preferably warm sunny summer days) at low tide, large groups of walkers take to the mud along the north coast of Fryslân and walk across the mudflats to one of the islands that lie a few kilometers off the coast. It’s decidedly muddy and, at times, extremely wet as on some stretches walkers are chest-deep in the sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No way was I going to take my shiny new DSLR on a risky trip like that. So, out came the trusty XA and a few rolls of black and white film. It took most of the day, but we made it to the island of Ameland, tired, wet, and very salty, but not too muddy because the deeper channel had washed the worst off.  Then we had to dash back to the main town on the island to catch the ferry back to the mainland. Wadlopen was a lot more fun than it sounds. A few hours later, back in my apartment in Amsterdam I headed straight into a much-needed shower and immediately tripped getting in, breaking my toe. Such is life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My absolute last outing with the XA was on a photo-walk in Shanghai in 2016. I took the XA and my Fujifilm X100T. During the walk, it was clear that the rangefinder window was misaligned, so I couldn’t trust the focus. I’ve yet to process those films (that’s them in the photo at the top of this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll finish with a few photos of wadlopen in the Netherlands. All the best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 1&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 2&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 3&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 4&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 5&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 6&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="cameras" /><category term="photography" /><category term="gas" /><category term="autobiographical" /><category term="Olympus XA" /><category term="Olympus" /><category term="Racal" /><category term="Decca" /><category term="houston" /><category term="texas" /><category term="louisiana" /><category term="snakes" /><category term="alligators" /><category term="wadlopen" /><category term="netherlandscode" /><summary type="html">Nothing could have prepared me for the intense heat and humidity of Houston, Texas, in the late summer of 1984, when I arrived there for my first overseas posting. Even the TV weather forecasts couldn’t cope when screen weather tickers topped out at 99% humidity for the simple reason that they couldn’t handle the three digits required to display 100%.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.tramfishers.com/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/oly.jpg%22%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.tramfishers.com/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/oly.jpg%22%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>