<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-12T14:32:05+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">TramFishers</title><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><entry><title type="html">Life Under Lockdown</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/06/life-under-lockdown/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Under Lockdown" /><published>2020-02-06T13:52:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-02-06T13:52:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/06/life-under-lockdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/06/life-under-lockdown/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/masked.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Shanghai during the current coronavirus outbreak, I’m often asked by overseas friends, how we are doing. The short form answer to that is, “We’re fine”. But here’s a longer update on the situation to date from the perspective of an expat in Shanghai.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first became aware of the virus around the beginning of January. It didn’t have a name then. At that point it was just some online rumblings about Wuhan. Thinking back, those rumblings would, even then, have been on international sites, maybe on Twitter. Certainly not from Chinese media sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were somewhat preoccupied at that time as our son, Ken, was due for a visit and had experienced some issues with his visa application, literally picking up his visa the day before he flew. We also had more family planning a visit in mid-February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Ken finally made it to Shanghai, and we quickly booked a short trip to Okinawa after the schools broke up for Chinese New Year. The virus still wasn’t really on the radar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were in Japan, the stories started to appear on Chinese social media sites and went, as it were, viral. We stocked up in face masks (not the best kind, but better than nothing) and duly wore them on our return flight to Shanghai on January 22nd. Everyone on that flight, including airline employees, was wearing a mask. We joked about the air marshal’s chances of success with facial recognition software as he did his preflight scan of the passengers with his body cam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our return, we’ve basically shut ourselves in the apartment only going out for necessities. The supermarket is open and has good stocks of fresh produce, but online retailers are gradually starting up again after the holiday, and they usually deliver within an hour or two, so we can avoid the supermarket too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One hiccup with the delivery situation occurred when a resident of our building spotted a delivery guy remove his mask in the elevator and spit in the corner. That led to an instant ban on outsiders from our compound. Now, they have to wait at the gate and call us to come and collect our deliveries. A small price for us to pay, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ken was due to return to his base in Dublin on February 4th. However, on the 27th, rumours about airlines cancelling direct flights started to circulate. Ken checked one of his aviation news sites (he’s an airline pilot) and read reports that BA had already suspended flights. A quick call to the BA call centre confirmed that this wasn’t the case, yet, and he managed to change his return flight to the 29th instead. About an hour later, major news sites broke the story that BA had suspended all flights with immediate effect. He called the call centre again, and they only learned of the suspension while he was talking to them, and telling them it was front page news on the BBC. Luckily, he was able to find an alternative flight on Emirates and departed that evening. A week early, but out, and able to go back to work as planned this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the story broke that the UK government was advising all UK citizens to leave China. Frankly, that strikes me more as an announcement calculated to generate headlines (distracting from what, I wonder), than as any sign of concern for the welfare of UK citizens in China. To date, I know of nobody in Shanghai who has been contacted by the UK consulate for any reason during this outbreak, perhaps the consular staff have already gone home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s about where we stand. Keeping heads down and waiting it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:-)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">Living in Shanghai during the current coronavirus outbreak, I’m often asked by overseas friends, how we are doing. The short form answer to that is, “We’re fine”. But here’s a longer update on the situation to date from the perspective of an expat in Shanghai.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Life in Cameras</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/a-life-in-cameras-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Life in Cameras" /><published>2020-01-31T11:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-01-31T11:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/a-life-in-cameras-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/a-life-in-cameras-2/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/cameras/fed.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second of a series of posts dedicated to the many cameras that I have owned over the years. While some posts may focus on my thoughts about the camera itself, for others, I hope to dig up some remote memories and anecdotes from the time when I owned it.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing this second article has taken a bit longer than expected. The problem is that this article and several future articles will touch on the same subject. It’s not a difficult subject, but I don’t want to start repeating myself without having something new to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought my first &lt;em&gt;serious&lt;/em&gt; camera, a Russian made FED 4 rangefinder, in my late teens. The decision to buy a rangefinder was probably 90% influence from my father. He was a huge fan of Leica and its rangefinders, and he instilled that sentiment in me with his enthusiasm. Sadly, he would never own a Leica although, years later, he did get to play with one of the early Leica digital models when I brought it back from Amsterdam. Maybe I’ll return to that story in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s about it for camera talk in this post. The FED 4 wasn’t a great camera but it served me well for a couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is more about missed opportunities and choices made at that time that can never be rectified. To tell that story, we need to start much more recently. On December 29th, 2019, the famous Scottish author, Alasdair Gray died. I confess that I had never read any of his books and wasn’t fully aware of his status and legacy. However, I did remember, as an 18-year-old student in Glasgow in 1981, seeing his first and most famous novel “Lanark” prominently displayed in the city’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mycityglasgow.co.uk/index_files/johnsmith.htm&quot;&gt;book shops&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember being intrigued by this odd looking book with the naked woman on the cover, but I never bought it, because of the naked woman on the cover. As a teenager, still living at home with my parents, I felt that the anticipated explanations required for the inevitable questions that would be asked far outweighed my desire to read the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to January 2020 and I’m looking for something to read. Having read the obituaries for Gray I was now aware that “Lanark” was probably one of the most important and influential works of Scottish literature of the 20th Century so it made sense to finally read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading this book has been an eye-opener. The main character, Thaw is growing up in the Riddrie area of Glasgow during the Second World War. My father grew up in Riddrie at that time. Later, after the war is over, Thaw attends Whitehill Senior Secondary School. In the book, Gray paints a vivid picture of the teaching staff. My father attended Whitehill Senior Secondary School at that time. Thaw’s father takes a job building the reservoir at Hogganfield. My grandparents lived just across the road from what became known as Hogganfield Loch. I remember it well, though I didn’t realise it was such a recent addition to the landscape. A little &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Alasdair_Gray&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; shows that this part of the book semi-autobiographical as it mirrors Gray’s early life. He grew up in Riddrie and attended Whitehill Senior Secondary School at the same time as my father.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/a7/c1/31/a7c1315001ba76f3241159f45760e6a4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px;&quot; title=&quot;Whitehill Senior Secondary School&quot; alt=&quot;Whitehill Senior Secondary School&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many missed opportunities. Had I bought this book when it first came out it would have opened up so many chances to learn about my father’s childhood and education. I would love to know if the teachers described in the book bear any relationship to actual teachers of the period. I’d also love to know if my father was aware of this kid, a couple of years younger than him, who was destined for such literary greatness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, opportunities lost due to the shy reluctance of the teenage me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="cameras" /><category term="photography" /><category term="gas" /><category term="fed" /><category term="rangefinder" /><category term="leicamount" /><category term="Leica" /><category term="biographical" /><category term="Whitehill Senior Secondary School" /><category term="Riddrie" /><category term="Glasgow" /><category term="Alasdair Gray" /><category term="Lanark" /><summary type="html">Second of a series of posts dedicated to the many cameras that I have owned over the years. While some posts may focus on my thoughts about the camera itself, for others, I hope to dig up some remote memories and anecdotes from the time when I owned it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/fed.jpg%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mayflower 400 - Mayflower II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/22/mayflower-400/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mayflower 400 - Mayflower II" /><published>2019-12-22T11:40:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-12-22T11:40:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/22/mayflower-400</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/22/mayflower-400/">&lt;p&gt;This morning I learned, through a retweet from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nicklewis&quot;&gt;@NickLewis&lt;/a&gt; of a tweet by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mayflower400uk&quot;&gt;@Mayflower400Uk&lt;/a&gt;, that 2020 will be the 400th anniversary of the voyage of the Mayflower. It reminded me of a family link to the Mayflower and a personal anecdote from about 20 years ago related to that link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/mayflowerII.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 40%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, the family link is not with the Mayflower that sailed almost 400 years ago, it’s with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Mayflower_II&quot;&gt;Mayflower II&lt;/a&gt; replica that made the same crossing in 1957.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mayflower II was built in Brixham, Devon in the mid-1950s. As an aside, I spent many weeks in Brixham in the mid-‘80s, but that’s not the link, maybe I’ll save that for a future post. One of the goals of the Mayflower II was to keep everything as authentic and true to the original as possible. Obviously it was required by law to carry more modern safety devices, but apart from that, everything was as close as possible to a 17th century merchant ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Craftsmen from all over the UK were called to produce the fittings for the ship. One of those fittings was a replica of the captain’s chest for his cabin. This was a rectangular wooden box, about a meter long and perhaps fifty centimetres tall and deep. It was covered by a flat wooden lid attached with two wrought iron hinges. Those hinges were made by my grandfather, James Smith, in Glasgow. At that time, he was running the family business, “R Smith and Co.”, a company that specialised in architectural iron work. Although the company is long gone, some of Glasgow’s most famous buildings are still graced with its wrought ironwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard the story of the hinges on the Mayflower II a few times when I was growing up. My father was posted to Germany in the army at the time they were made so he never saw them. He didn’t think he would ever have the chance to see them so it was just a story to tell the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the late ’90s. I found myself in a job that was taking me to Boston several times a year. I decided to extend one of my trips into a vacation and invited my parents to join me. It was a chance to tour New England and, of course, to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plimoth.org/&quot;&gt;Plimoth Plantation&lt;/a&gt; where the Mayflower II is on display. In the weeks before the trip Dad emailed Plimoth Plantation to ask if it would be possible to see the chest with his father’s hinges. The answer from the museum curator was positive. While the chest wasn’t currently on display, it was in storage and she would be happy to show it to us when we arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at the museum, after touring the Mayflower II, we headed to the admin offices to meet up with the curator that my Dad had been in contact with. She took us in an elevator down into the bowels of the building where we found ourselves in a large, slightly musty smelling, storage room filled with rows of shelving, all stacked with artefacts. She took us to a row where we saw two large, very similar, chests, wrapped in heavy clear plastic for protection. She unwrapped one, and there it was, the 1950s replica chest, complete with my Grandfather’s hinges. We had a good look and took some photos (sadly lost now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were (literally) wrapping up I was slightly confused. Our family story only ever included a single chest so this second chest was a surprise, I asked the curator if she knew anything of its story and where it came from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh yes.” she replied, “That’s the captain’s chest from the original Mayflower.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="history" /><category term="anecdote" /><category term="iron" /><category term="mayflower400" /><summary type="html">This morning I learned, through a retweet from @NickLewis of a tweet by @Mayflower400Uk, that 2020 will be the 400th anniversary of the voyage of the Mayflower. It reminded me of a family link to the Mayflower and a personal anecdote from about 20 years ago related to that link.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Steve Howe Trio - New Frontier</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/30/steve-howe-trio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Steve Howe Trio - New Frontier" /><published>2019-10-30T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-30T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/30/steve-howe-trio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/30/steve-howe-trio/">&lt;p&gt;Really enjoying the jazzy Yes vibes of this new album from &lt;em&gt;The Steve Howe Trio&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative; padding-bottom: 50%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 50%;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://embed.tidal.com/albums/116732497?layout=gridify&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 1px; min-height: 100%; margin: 0 auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a huge &lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt; fan for around 40 years or so. It’s good to hear shades of Howe’s distinctive guitar sound in this, altogether, more mellow setting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="music" /><category term="jazz" /><category term="prog" /><category term="true" /><category term="Steve Howe" /><summary type="html">Really enjoying the jazzy Yes vibes of this new album from The Steve Howe Trio.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chrome Dark Mode</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/23/chrome-dark-mode/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chrome Dark Mode" /><published>2019-10-23T15:55:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-23T15:55:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/23/chrome-dark-mode</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/23/chrome-dark-mode/">&lt;p&gt;Google Chrome version 78 has just launched. I was having a look at the “chrome://flags” page and discovered that it’s now possible to enable dark mode for all sites in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, enter &lt;a href=&quot;chrome://flags&quot;&gt;chrome://flags&lt;/a&gt; in the url bar and then, when the page loads, search for “dark”. You should see the two settings shown in the image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/ChromeDarkMode.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select one of the choices for &lt;strong&gt;“Force Dark Mode for Web Content”&lt;/strong&gt; from the drop down menu on the right and click the button at the bottom right of the screen to relaunch your browser. I’m not sure what all the options do, but I found that &lt;strong&gt;“Enabled with selective inversion of everything”&lt;/strong&gt; works quite well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to switch it off again, just repeat the above and set the dropdown to &lt;strong&gt;“Disabled”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>FrasSmith</name></author><category term="chrome" /><category term="google" /><category term="DarkMode" /><category term="tips" /><summary type="html">Google Chrome version 78 has just launched. I was having a look at the “chrome://flags” page and discovered that it’s now possible to enable dark mode for all sites in the browser. As mentioned, enter chrome://flags in the url bar and then, when the page loads, search for “dark”. You should see the two settings shown in the image below. Select one of the choices for “Force Dark Mode for Web Content” from the drop down menu on the right and click the button at the bottom right of the screen to relaunch your browser. I’m not sure what all the options do, but I found that “Enabled with selective inversion of everything” works quite well. If you want to switch it off again, just repeat the above and set the dropdown to “Disabled”. Enjoy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/ChromeDarkMode.png%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet The New Head of Security</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/22/head-of-security/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet The New Head of Security" /><published>2019-10-22T15:27:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-22T15:27:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/22/head-of-security</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/22/head-of-security/">&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B35vyINgY3B/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B35vyINgY3B/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B35vyINgY3B/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meet the new head of security... #mono #monochromatic #maniquinhead #maniquinchallenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/frassmith/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Fraser Smith&lt;/a&gt; (@frassmith) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-10-22T01:37:10+00:00&quot;&gt;Oct 21, 2019 at 6:37pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>FrasSmith</name></author><category term="instagram" /><category term="maniquin" /><category term="hairdressers" /><category term="mono" /><category term="monochrome" /><summary type="html">View this post on Instagram Meet the new head of security... #mono #monochromatic #maniquinhead #maniquinchallenge A post shared by Fraser Smith (@frassmith) on Oct 21, 2019 at 6:37pm PDT</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dune Remake Wraps Production</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/dune-movie/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dune Remake Wraps Production" /><published>2019-10-18T16:51:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-18T16:51:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/dune-movie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/18/dune-movie/">&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Ffras.smith%2Fposts%2F10157819450407652&amp;amp;width=500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;482&quot; style=&quot;border:none;overflow:hidden&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>FrasSmith</name></author><category term="movies" /><category term="scifi" /><category term="ScienceFiction" /><category term="Dune" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Life in Cameras</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/17/a-life-in-cameras-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Life in Cameras" /><published>2019-10-17T11:01:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-17T11:01:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/17/a-life-in-cameras-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/17/a-life-in-cameras-1/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/cameras/instamatic.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first of a series of posts dedicated to the many cameras that I have owned over the years. While some of the posts may focus on my thoughts the camera itself, for others, I hope to dig up some remote memories and anecdotes from the time when I owned it.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around about 1968, my parents gave my sister and I Kodak Instamatic cameras as Christmas presents, I was five years old and it was my first real camera. My dad was a keen photographer and had been using his Kodak Retina 1b since 1956 and mum also had a slightly more advanced Instamatic. We were a true Kodak family in those days. It took &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/126_film&quot;&gt;126 cartridge film&lt;/a&gt; and I still remember the agonizing wait for the exposed films (12 exposures) to return from the developers. The pictures were square, but there were special offers at that time that would print a 4” print and two 2” prints of each image on a single 6”x4” print. I’ve no idea what the point was, but we thought it was cool at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first memory of actually using a camera is probably from the following spring or summer. I can remember that there had been few opportunities to use our Christmas present cameras up until then, so, at the first sign of some warmer weather, the whole family piled into our Vauxhall Viva and headed off to Arbroath on the Scottish east coast. It was lambing season. The fields were full of happy gambolling lambs. We soon pulled over for a photo opportunity. My sister and I stood, cameras at the ready, determined to get the shot and not waste any of our precious twelve exposures. Even in those days, I was already on the lookout for something different, something that would give my image a certain &lt;em&gt;je ne sais quoi&lt;/em&gt;. The opportunity soon presented itself and I snapped my first masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mummy, Mummy,” I said, tugging at her sleeve, “I took a photo of a lamb sitting down.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lambs don’t sit down,” she answered patiently, “it must have been…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly, it dawned on me. I felt my face redden with embarrassment. My first photographic masterpiece. Indeed, the earliest photographic experience that I remember to this day, was of a sheep having a pee.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>FrasSmith</name></author><category term="cameras" /><category term="photography" /><category term="gas" /><category term="kodak" /><category term="instamatic" /><category term="biographical" /><summary type="html">This is the first of a series of posts dedicated to the many cameras that I have owned over the years. While some of the posts may focus on my thoughts the camera itself, for others, I hope to dig up some remote memories and anecdotes from the time when I owned it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/instamatic.jpg%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kubernetes Poem</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/17/kubernetes-poem/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kubernetes Poem" /><published>2019-10-17T10:47:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-17T10:47:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/17/kubernetes-poem</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/17/kubernetes-poem/">&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-partner=&quot;tweetdeck&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Groan... &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/TFV4gLUECx&quot;&gt;https://t.co/TFV4gLUECx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; LiteraVerse (@LiteraVerse) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LiteraVerse/status/1184661907900260352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 17, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>LiteraVerse</name></author><summary type="html">Groan... https://t.co/TFV4gLUECx&amp;mdash; LiteraVerse (@LiteraVerse) October 17, 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Posting to Instagram from the Desktop</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/15/posting-to-instagram-from-desktop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Posting to Instagram from the Desktop" /><published>2019-10-15T22:08:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-15T22:08:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/15/posting-to-instagram-from-desktop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/15/posting-to-instagram-from-desktop/">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest frustrations for photographers when using &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; is its mobile only ethos. For any photographer, uploading images to Instagram can be a chore as a typical workflow would be to transfer files from camera to computer, process files, export to jpeg and then, find some way to transfer the jpeg files onto a phone to upload to Instagram. It’s almost as if Instagram doesn’t really want serious photographers on its platform.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
There are a few tutorials online that outline various methods to work around this limitation. A common solution is to install some form of Android emulator or VM and then install the Instagram app there. This is over complicated and a huge resource drain for such a single use requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method described here is much simpler and uses an app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;, that you probably already have installed on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most users will be familiar with the Instagram app on iPhone or Android devices. However, what many don’t realise is that the app is not mandatory. You can use the Instagram web site on any mobile browser too. The site automatically detects that it’s running in a mobile browser and includes the toolbar, including the upload button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/instamenu.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be great if you could make the Instagram site on your desktop browser think that it’s running on a mobile? Well, you can. Every browser sends a unique identifier to each website that it accesses, describing the platform that it’s running on. This identifier, called the User-Agent, is what the site uses to decide whether it’s responding to a mobile or a computer. There are extensions available for most popular desktop browsers that will allow you to manually set the User-Agent string to any value you want, allowing your desktop browser to identify as a mobile device if you wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Chrome, one such extension is &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/user-agent-switcher-for-c/djflhoibgkdhkhhcedjiklpkjnoahfmg&quot;&gt;User-Agent Switcher for Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. Install this extension and you’ll be able to configure it to use a User-Agent string for a mobile device whenever you access Instagram. Instagram will then serve up its mobile site complete with toolbar and function exactly as if its running on a mobile device. Quick, simple and no need to emulate anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/desktop.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>FrasSmith</name></author><category term="instagram" /><category term="photography" /><category term="howto" /><category term="tips" /><category term="chrome" /><summary type="html">One of the biggest frustrations for photographers when using Instagram is its mobile only ethos. For any photographer, uploading images to Instagram can be a chore as a typical workflow would be to transfer files from camera to computer, process files, export to jpeg and then, find some way to transfer the jpeg files onto a phone to upload to Instagram. It’s almost as if Instagram doesn’t really want serious photographers on its platform.</summary></entry></feed>