<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-18T19:03:01+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">TramFishers</title><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><entry><title type="html">Camera Life 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/18/camera-life-4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camera Life 4" /><published>2020-03-18T18:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-18T18:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/18/camera-life-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/18/camera-life-4">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/cameras/oly-bw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Olympus XA Camera plus film&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nothing could have prepared me for the intense heat and humidity of Houston, Texas in the late summer of 1984 when I arrived there for my first overseas posting. Even the TV weather forecasts couldn’t cope when screen weather tickers topped out at 99% humidity for the simple reason that they couldn’t handle the three digits required to display 100%.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduating from college in 1983, I spent the summer months working in a Hi-fi shop in Glasgow while I looked for a full-time job. I found that job in the autumn and started my training in a few weeks before Christmas. Very early on, I learned that the job would entail a lot of overseas travel and that I would be spending a lot of time at sea. It seemed that traveling light would be the order of the day and I wouldn’t be able to take my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/03/11/a-life-in-cameras-3&quot;&gt;SLR and lenses&lt;/a&gt; with me on my trips. A smaller camera was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job was with a company called Racal Survey, although, in many parts of the world, it was still known by its more historically famous name Decca Survey. As an aside Decca Survey was a separate company from Decca Records, the company that infamously rejected The Beatles. Decca Survey was more famous as the company built out the technological advances in navigation made during World War Two that enabled the thousand bomber raids over Germany by using its accurate (for the time) navigation network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My 21st birthday was in February 1984, so I asked my sister and brother-in-law for a new camera as a birthday gift. The camera that I chose was the very compact and entirely pocketable Olympus XA. I could write hundreds of words about this camera but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.casualphotophile.com/2018/06/20/olympus-xa-review-35mm-film-camera-rangefinder/&quot;&gt;Casual Photo File&lt;/a&gt; does a much better job than I could and I’m not trying to write about cameras per se.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The XA became my carry-everywhere camera for the next fifteen years or so. Right up until I bought my first digital camera in the late nineties. Even after that, I have still run the occasional roll of film through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several training courses in the UK and a couple of offshore jobs in the North Sea, I was ready for my first overseas posting, Houston, Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steamy as Houston was, it was nothing compared to the location for my first assignment of that trip. After a week in the office acclimatizing, I was given a pickup truck and sent to look after a system monitoring station on the gulf coast of Louisiana. &lt;img src=&quot;/img/fs-houston.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FS in Houston, 1984&quot; class=&quot;lft&quot; /&gt;The station itself consisted of a 10 m antenna erected at the edge of a small trailer park some ten miles off the main road and a mile or two from the coast. The monitoring equipment was housed in one of the trailers. It turned out that this was where I too was to be housed for the next three weeks. Whoa, three years of study and, a year after graduation, I’m living in a trailer park in rural Louisiana. That was unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life in the trailer park was “interesting”. I soon learned to be careful when putting the trash out as some small black slithery, almost certainly venomous, wildlife liked to hide in the shade under the bin. I was glad to see that they were just as worried about me as I was about them as they disappeared with some speed when exposed. &lt;img src=&quot;/img/gulf-sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset on the Gulf of Mexico 1984&quot; class=&quot;rght&quot; /&gt; Every evening in the dusk, I was entertained by a light show from thousands of fireflies at the edge of the nearby wood. My neighbors told me that there were alligators in the area too although I never managed to see any, even after making a couple of special trips to the places where they were supposed to hang out. I did see a few later in the trip when I had to over-fly the region in a helicopter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also entertained by my trailer park neighbor, Lionel (“Lah’own’eyll”) and his timid wife, Dolly. In the politically incorrect words (even then) of my Texan colleagues, Lionel was a “coon-ass”, the Louisiana equivalent of a “red-neck” in Texas. Basically, he was poor, white, and rural. He was a big man, best described as the human equivalent in stature and speech of &lt;a href=&quot;https://looneytunes.fandom.com/wiki/Foghorn_Leghorn&quot;&gt;Foghorn Leghorn&lt;/a&gt; the Looney Tunes cartoon rooster. Lionel, it turned out, liked to do odd jobs and, according to Lionel, my predecessors always paid him $20 to cut the grass around the antenna. I’m not sure if that was entirely true, but I was happy enough to give him the work because it was a large area and the days were hot. This paid off as Lionel then offered to introduce me to Gumbo, “dat’s good eat’n boy, good eat’n” is how I remember him describing it to me. What he omitted to explain was that he was going to cook this crab gumbo (an all-day affair) in my trailer, on my stove, using my gas. I think I ended up paying for the crabs as well. No matter, it was good eat’n.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have several more stories from this period maybe I’ll revisit it in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my last &lt;em&gt;successful&lt;/em&gt; outing with the Olympus XA was almost twenty years later in the Netherlands. Long after leaving Racal, I was working on a publishing project in Amsterdam. A dutch friend invited me to join her on a peculiarly dutch activity called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wadlopen.net/&quot;&gt;wadlopen&lt;/a&gt;. On certain days (preferably warm sunny summer days) at low tide, large groups of walkers take to the mud along the north coast of Fryslân and walk across the mudflats to one of the islands that lie a few kilometers off the coast. It’s decidedly muddy and, at times, extremely wet as on some stretches walkers are chest-deep in the sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No way was I going to take my shiny new DSLR on a risky trip like that. So, out came the trusty XA and a few rolls of black and white film. It took most of the day, but we made it to the island of Ameland, tired, wet, and very salty, but not too muddy because the deeper channel had washed the worst off.  Then we had to dash back to the main town on the island to catch the ferry back to the mainland. Wadlopen was a lot more fun than it sounds. A few hours later, back in my apartment in Amsterdam I headed straight into a much-needed shower and immediately tripped getting in, breaking my toe. Such is life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My absolute last outing with the XA was on a photo-walk in Shanghai in 2016. I took the XA and my Fujifilm X100T. During the walk, it was clear that the rangefinder window was misaligned, so I couldn’t trust the focus. I’ve yet to process those films (that’s them in the photo at the top of this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll finish with a few photos of wadlopen in the Netherlands. All the best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 1&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 2&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 3&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 4&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 5&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 6&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="cameras" /><category term="photography" /><category term="gas" /><category term="autobiographical" /><category term="Olympus XA" /><category term="Olympus" /><category term="Racal" /><category term="Decca" /><summary type="html">Nothing could have prepared me for the intense heat and humidity of Houston, Texas in the late summer of 1984 when I arrived there for my first overseas posting. Even the TV weather forecasts couldn’t cope when screen weather tickers topped out at 99% humidity for the simple reason that they couldn’t handle the three digits required to display 100%.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/oly.jpg%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Camera Life 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/11/a-life-in-cameras-3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camera Life 3" /><published>2020-03-11T17:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-11T17:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/11/a-life-in-cameras-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/11/a-life-in-cameras-3">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/cameras/xgm-banner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Minolta Camera&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I often think of the XG/M as my first SLR camera. It wasn’t. I’d had a Praktica SLR for some time already, but I had no lenses other than the kit lens and it used a screw mount which was notoriously tricky and slow to use. So, the Minolta with its bayonet mount was the first SLR that I had additional lenses for, the first one that I took seriously. However, this post isn’t about that camera (well, maybe it is a little).&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t remember the first time I went to G. E. Williamson’s camera shop in Glasgow’s Sauchiehall Street, but I do know that it was the first of many visits and several purchases. The most significant of these purchases was the Minolta XG/M SLR camera that is, nominally, the subject of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September 1980, I became a student at Glasgow College of Technology (now known as Glasgow Caledonian University). I was lucky to qualify for a student grant, but I also wanted to supplement that with some regular income. I had been given the name of Tom Simmonds, the manager at James Kerr and Co., a high-end Hi-fi shop in Woodlands Road. Over the summer before I started college, I pestered this poor man with multiple phone calls asking if they had any Saturday jobs. At first, he had tried to fob me off by saying that he didn’t know and that I should call back in a week or two. I don’t think he expected me to do that. But I did. A few times. Finally, he invited me in for a chat. And that was it, I had a Saturday job earning the princely sum of £10 per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Williamson’s was nearby and it became a regular stop on my Saturday lunch breaks. In character, it was very similar to Kerr’s. They were both from an older time. A time when wood, not aluminium or steel, was the primary building material for shop furniture. Glass topped counters with narrow wooden frames that doubled as display cases for smaller goods. Smoke had yellowed the walls, visible only between display cases and dog-eared advertising posters. In Williamson’s, the end of the shop was dedicated to tripods and lighting stands, in Kerr’s, to speakers. In both cases, the staff worked there because they were knowledgeable about the products on sale and could spend time with a customer to ensure that they bought the right product. This knowledge and attitude resulted in long term customers and repeat purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time that I worked at James Kerr and Co., the eponymous founder was no longer on the scene. The owner at that time was his co-founder Ted McCosh. Ted was every bit the country gentleman, commuting from a long way out of town. He had a brusque nature and didn’t suffer fools gladly. Ted was a tall, almost gaunt, figure that I never saw wear anything but tweed, regardless of the time of year. He’d march in every morning at around eleven, a huge loose-leaf folder under his arm, with barely a nod to any staff in the shop and head straight to his office in the back where he’d immediately light up one of his Senior Service untipped cigarettes. For the first year or so, I lived in fear of getting on the wrong side of him although I learned later that he could be quite friendly once he got to know you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up working for Kerr’s for several years; Saturdays during term time, and full-time during the holidays. My last dealing with Ted was just before I left to take up a full-time job after graduation. I’d had my eye on an old Thorens TD-150 turntable in the stockroom. It dated from the late ’60s and had been Mr. Lancaster’s (one of our long term regular customers). Ted sold it to me for £13. It was a good buy. I sold it over twenty years later to a man from the BBC for significantly more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s ironic that when I was thinking about this post, which was to be about G. E. Williamson’s, I could remember so many details about the shop and its staff but I couldn’t remember the name. I searched online but found nothing. Finally, I asked my sister if she or my brother-in-law knew? They didn’t, but she suggested I ask Ron Young. Ron was an old friend of the family from that time, a member of the same Scout group as me, and is now a professional photographer. As my sister pointed out, he also worked at that end of town for a while. I found Ron’s email address on his website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ronyoungphotography.co.uk/RON_YOUNG_PHOTOGRAPHY/profile.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Ronald Young Photography”&lt;/a&gt;. Ron did indeed know the name of the shop. He also reminded me of the fact that he had also worked at James Kerr and Co. when he was a student, a few years before me. It was Ron who had given me Tom Simmonds as the person to contact to ask for a job. I also learned from Ron, that Ted McCosh bought his camera equipment from Williamson’s and was friends with George Williamson the founder and owner of that shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a short email conversation, we speculated about what became of Tom and Ted. I managed to find a Daily Telegraph notice online. Ted passed away in 2010 at his home in Lanarkshire. He was 84 years old. As a 17-year-old part-time shop assistant, I had always thought of him as being old. In truth, when I started at Kerr’s, this gruff, scary man, Ted, was 53. Four years younger than I am now. That’s certainly something to make you think.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="cameras" /><category term="photography" /><category term="gas" /><category term="autobiographical" /><category term="Glasgow" /><category term="Minolta XG/M" /><category term="Minolta" /><category term="SLR" /><category term="G. E. Williamsons" /><category term="James Kerr and Co." /><category term="Glasgow" /><summary type="html">I often think of the XG/M as my first SLR camera. It wasn’t. I’d had a Praktica SLR for some time already, but I had no lenses other than the kit lens and it used a screw mount which was notoriously tricky and slow to use. So, the Minolta with its bayonet mount was the first SLR that I had additional lenses for, the first one that I took seriously. However, this post isn’t about that camera (well, maybe it is a little).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/xgm.jpg%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Five Things to do Under Lockdown</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/04/five-things-to-do-under-lockdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five Things to do Under Lockdown" /><published>2020-03-04T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-04T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/04/five-things-to-do-under-lockdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/04/five-things-to-do-under-lockdown">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/garlic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Time to learn to cook some garlic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are at post number 5 about life under lockdown in Shanghai. As the situation shows signs of improvement in China but deteriorates in other countries, I bring you some suggestions, in no particular order of importance, for those about to experience their own life under lockdown.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is probably a no-brainer for anyone who has a job, but finds that they are unable to go to their place of work. I’m lucky, I’m already a remote worker so adjusting to lockdown life hasn’t been difficult for me. My advice to those of you experiencing this for the first time is to “set boundaries”, both physical, and chronological. Try to find a location where you can work uninterrupted by your family and focus on your work. However, just because your place of work is now within your home, that doesn’t mean you have to work at all hours of the day. Try to keep to normal business hours.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Of course, with family at home too and possibly with kids taking part in e-learning program, this may not always be easy. Flexibility will be required.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This has been quite a common pastime for people under lockdown in China. It makes sense. If you’re out at work all day, the last thing you want to do when you get home is spend hours in the kitchen preparing a meal. It’s all too easy to order takeaway or warm up left-overs from the weekend. Suddenly, you find yourself with time on your hands. Why not open that recipe page on your smartphone and have some fun?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I confess that this has applied more to my wife than to me, but I have managed to bake some garlic (Yay! I’m a kitchen hero!) and produce a pretty mean baked spaghetti casserole sort of thing where the ingredients at hand didn’t properly overlap with those required by the recipe. I improvised. Nobody complained, seconds were requested, and we all survived.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep Fit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;No more commute. No more visits to the gym (as if I ever did). All that great(?) new food. It all takes its toll on the waistline. You need to do something to compensate for all the everyday exercise that you’re missing due to lockdown. I have an exercise bike (two years old, very low mileage, one careful owner) that I’ve reluctantly started using again to (in Apple parlance) &lt;em&gt;close my ring&lt;/em&gt; every day. You don’t need a bike, I’m sure you can find your own preferred means to &lt;em&gt;close your ring&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try a new hobby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;You’re going to have time on your hands. Take this as an opportunity try a new hobby or learn something you’ve always wanted to learn but have never had the time for. I’ve always wanted to do more writing. Even a short stint at a reasonably famous tech blog, that let’s be honest, I didn’t enjoy at all (they sacked me, and I was so glad) didn’t kill that desire.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This lockdown plus me hearing about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.write52.com/&quot;&gt;Write52&lt;/a&gt; project at the beginning has resulted in these posts. Five down, forty-seven to go.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch obscure stuff and learn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Ok, this one is a bit obscure. I tend to watch a lot of videos on YouTube in the evenings. Photography and science videos are a favourite. With more time, I found I was running out of my staples and I strayed into geekier territory. It’s great, honestly. I can watch and learn at the same time. For the techies out there I have actually found myself; watching geeks do presentations about ‘vim’ and ‘emacs’; I’ve watched people live stream Windows XP installations; I’ve… well enough. I think I’ve dug a deep enough hole already.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;My point is, there’s lots out there and there’s no harm in following random interests to keep the brain cells ticking over.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;All the best.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="covid-19" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">So here we are at post number 5 about life under lockdown in Shanghai. As the situation shows signs of improvement in China but deteriorates in other countries, I bring you some suggestions, in no particular order of importance, for those about to experience their own life under lockdown.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life Under Lockdown 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/26/life-under-lockdown-4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Under Lockdown 4" /><published>2020-02-26T19:30:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-02-26T19:30:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/26/life-under-lockdown-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/26/life-under-lockdown-4">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/train.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Childrens Train Ride under wraps&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the final update about life under lockdown in Shanghai. While it will probably be a few weeks before normality returns (if it ever does return), there are signs of improvement in Shanghai.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a quiet week in Shanghai with few developments on the virus front. Few developments in this context is a good thing because it literally means no new cases in the city for several days. However, as we hope that China may have passed the peak, it seems the rest of the world is just getting started. A few weeks ago at the start of our lockdown, we discussed whether we should leave the country for the duration. We stayed. One of our concerns was that, wherever we went, the covid-19 virus might follow. Watching the reports of clusters appearing in Europe and elsewhere in Asia, I suspect that we may have made a good call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports of South Korean religious cults actively trying to spread the virus globally (Substantiated? Unsubstantiated? I don’t know at this point) are obviously worrying. More worrying, however, is thinking about how well-prepared western countries are for this epidemic. China is remarkably good at mobilizing its citizens in times of national emergency and simple things like mask wearing come as second nature to a population prepared by urban pollution. I’m not so sure that the major western democracies will be so successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the week that the government relaxed travel restrictions to allow people to finally return to the city after their extended Chinese New Year break and kick-start the economy which was probably hovering on the brink of recession. I read today that rush hour traffic in Shanghai was at 80%-90% of normal this morning. There were even some traffic jams. Mixed blessings I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a slightly more “meta” level, this site and specifically this series of posts got quite a boost yesterday when one of my tweets mentioning it was retweeted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neilhimself&quot;&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt;. This accounted for a nice uplift in views for the posts. Which was nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, will this be my final update in this series? Maybe next week I’ll return to my extremely sparse autobiographical series “A Life in Cameras”. I’m pretty sure that we’ll still be under lockdown here, but our position is becoming less unique. How many more people across the globe will be under lockdown next week?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take care, buy masks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="covid-19" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">Perhaps the final update about life under lockdown in Shanghai. While it will probably be a few weeks before normality returns (if it ever does return), there are signs of improvement in Shanghai.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life Under Lockdown 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/19/life-under-lockdown-3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Under Lockdown 3" /><published>2020-02-19T21:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-02-19T21:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/19/life-under-lockdown-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/19/life-under-lockdown-3">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/empty-road.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An Empty road in Shanghai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I wrote the original post in this series, I assumed it was going to be a single post. After the second, I thought that would be it. However, the situation is always fluid. Things change. So here we are with post number 3.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living under lockdown has become the new normal. We do still get out, but we try to only go out when it’s absolutely essential. In addition, we do have regular deliveries which entail a short walk to the gatehouse for collection. Having read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/02/15/business/china-coronavirus-lockdown.html&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, I guess we’re getting off quite lightly. Our apartment building stands alone in its own small compound. The residents are typically owner/occupiers and it’s small enough that the security staff and building management recognise the residents. The residents of larger, multi-apartment compounds in our neighbourhood don’t have such easy access. Many have instituted a pass system to prove residency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily’s unofficial e-learning began this week. Officially the full e-learning programs will start on March 2nd, but Emily is in an international division that chose to restart schooling, albeit remotely, on the original semester start date. After some initial reticence regarding the use of the video conferencing software, things are off and running. Each day commences with a class meeting with their form teacher before they either have more video lessons, do assignments, or Q&amp;amp;A sessions with their teachers. The workload has been high. Almost too high, but there are signs that this will settle down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charlotte’s elementary school sent out some extra homework to keep her busy. There was an 88 page book filled with Mandarin, English and Mathematics problems, as well as a few more relaxing things to make and do. Thankfully, there was a companion volume of answers for frazzled parents. The pack also included an MP3 file which turned out to be a recording of a patriotic song about all the heroic mums and dads (doctors and nurses) who had gone to Wuhan to fight the virus and care for the sick. Sigh. Propaganda like this is one of the downsides of sending kids to local schools. I’m glad to say that both my daughters (Emily spent 5 years in local primary as well before going to an international division) have enough critical thinking ability to recognise that there are certain aspects of the school system that they can safely ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nationwide travel disruption is now having a significant effect on logistics companies. Here in Shanghai, we had become spoiled by the convenience of being able to order goods before 11am and have them delivered within 6 hours. At first, the lockdown meant that same day delivery became next day delivery. Over the last week this has extended, and extended. For such orders, we now wait 2 or 3 days for warehouse processing and then a couple of days transit. Reduced staffing levels are probably the cause of delays as many employees may not have returned after the extended holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s about all from this week’s update. There are signs that the virus may have peaked: No new cases in Shanghai, for example, for several days. I seem to cope pretty well with the lockdown. I spent the first 10 years of my career working offshore. Life at sea wasn’t a lot different from our current situation although there was a greater chance of drowning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="covid-19" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">When I wrote the original post in this series, I assumed it was going to be a single post. After the second, I thought that would be it. However, the situation is always fluid. Things change. So here we are with post number 3.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life Under Lockdown 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/12/life-under-lockdown-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Under Lockdown 2" /><published>2020-02-12T17:45:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-02-12T17:45:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/12/life-under-lockdown-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/12/life-under-lockdown-2">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/skyway.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking up at Skyway Hotel&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I wrote the original &lt;a href=&quot;https://tramfishers.com/2020/02/06/life-under-lockdown/&quot;&gt;Life Under Lockdown&lt;/a&gt; post a week ago, I didn’t plan on making it a series, but here we are, one week later and I’m writing an update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a week of reflection, a week of getting enough sleep, a week of boredom and, sadly, a week marred by tragedy. It’s also been the week in which I completed my 57th orbit of the sun so yay for me.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The enforced extension to the Chinese New Year holiday has been pretty evident all week. The streets, normally a constant stream of cars and buses have been empty. Next to our apartment is a fifty floor hotel. Guessing that forty-five of those floors are given over to rooms with perhaps twenty-five rooms per floor, we can safely assume that it has well over one thousand rooms. Looking at it now, I can count maybe five rooms with lights on. That’s not good business. To think that’s just one of many hotels, restaurants and businesses that will be suffering financially during this crisis. How many will survive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning, I looked down at the hotel garden from our kitchen window. A single white egret flew down and landed on the grass. It’s quite common to see egrets by the riverside, a mile or so away, but I don’t remember ever seeing one near here. Perhaps the lack of people has made the birds feel safer. One door closes, another opens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical week for me involves a six o’clock start on week days to get my daughter Emily up and fed and then out the door to catch her seven o’clock school bus. I’m hopeless at early nights, so I’ve become used to six hours or less sleep per night. Now, under lockdown, I don’t need to wake up until eight-thirty. Not only am I feeling more rested, the quality of my sleep has improved too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m lucky that I typically work from home anyway so it’s not too difficult to adjust to this new lifestyle. Like many people, my wife is dealing with the boredom by having fun in the kitchen, experimenting with ideas and recipes that she would never have had time for in the past. Unfortunately boredom leads to reading more social media posts, some of which lean to the sensationalist end of the spectrum. One that my wife sent me, even after running through Google Translate, came out as something worthy of the nastiest tabloids with many headers pointing out the “unimaginable” horrors of coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The schools are starting to put their e-learning strategies into place. Officially, they won’t start until March 2nd. However, Emily’s school is planning to start remote video classes next week and has published quite an extensive timetable. Emily’s younger sister Charlotte’s elementary school has announced that they will start e-learning on March 2nd. It looks as if the kids will still be at home even after the March 2nd deadline. I guess we’re in this for the long haul. Meanwhile, the entrepreneurial spirit is kicking in. At least one online learning company has scheduled free daily live streams for Mandarin and English classes of all grades until the local schools implement their own e-learning program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entrepreneurial spirit is evident elsewhere too. Our apartment, like most in Shanghai has advertising video displays in the elevators. These now seem to be alternating patriotic videos of heroic doctors in Wuhan with advertisements for vitamin supplements (we’re all stuck at home, cooking lots, eating too much, and not exercising enough), silicone gloves (we don’t want to touch anything), and, yes, free online learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, something that brought everything into sharp perspective. A business associate and friend of my wife, architect Chen Zhanhui (Sunny), died suddenly of a heart attack on Sunday morning. He was fifty-one. He leaves a wife and two young daughters. We just learned today that his wife is pregnant. A sobering reminder that virus or no virus, life is precarious.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="covid-19" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">When I wrote the original Life Under Lockdown post a week ago, I didn’t plan on making it a series, but here we are, one week later and I’m writing an update. It’s been a week of reflection, a week of getting enough sleep, a week of boredom and, sadly, a week marred by tragedy. It’s also been the week in which I completed my 57th orbit of the sun so yay for me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life Under Lockdown</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/06/life-under-lockdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Under Lockdown" /><published>2020-02-06T13:52:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-02-06T13:52:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/06/life-under-lockdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/06/life-under-lockdown">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/masked.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Author in Mask&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in Shanghai during the current coronavirus outbreak, I’m often asked by overseas friends, how we are doing. The short form answer to that is, “We’re fine”. But here’s a longer update on the situation to date from the perspective of an expat in Shanghai.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first became aware of the virus around the beginning of January. It didn’t have a name then. At that point it was just some online rumblings about Wuhan. Thinking back, those rumblings would, even then, have been on international sites, maybe on Twitter. Certainly not from Chinese media sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were somewhat preoccupied at that time as our son, Ken, was due for a visit and had experienced some issues with his visa application, literally picking up his visa the day before he flew. We also had more family planning a visit in mid-February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Ken finally made it to Shanghai, and we quickly booked a short trip to Okinawa after the schools broke up for Chinese New Year. The virus still wasn’t really on the radar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were in Japan, the stories started to appear on Chinese social media sites and went, as it were, viral. We stocked up in face masks (not the best kind, but better than nothing) and duly wore them on our return flight to Shanghai on January 22nd. Everyone on that flight, including airline employees, was wearing a mask. We joked about the air marshal’s chances of success with facial recognition software as he did his preflight scan of the passengers with his body cam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our return, we’ve basically shut ourselves in the apartment only going out for necessities. The supermarket is open and has good stocks of fresh produce, but online retailers are gradually starting up again after the holiday, and they usually deliver within an hour or two, so we can avoid the supermarket too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One hiccup with the delivery situation occurred when a resident of our building spotted a delivery guy remove his mask in the elevator and spit in the corner. That led to an instant ban on outsiders from our compound. Now, they have to wait at the gate and call us to come and collect our deliveries. A small price for us to pay, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ken was due to return to his base in Dublin on February 4th. However, on the 27th, rumours about airlines cancelling direct flights started to circulate. Ken checked one of his aviation news sites (he’s an airline pilot) and read reports that BA had already suspended flights. A quick call to the BA call centre confirmed that this wasn’t the case, yet, and he managed to change his return flight to the 29th instead. About an hour later, major news sites broke the story that BA had suspended all flights with immediate effect. He called the call centre again, and they only learned of the suspension while he was talking to them, and telling them it was front page news on the BBC. Luckily, he was able to find an alternative flight on Emirates and departed that evening. A week early, but out, and able to go back to work as planned this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the story broke that the UK government was advising all UK citizens to leave China. Frankly, that strikes me more as an announcement calculated to generate headlines (distracting from what, I wonder), than as any sign of concern for the welfare of UK citizens in China. To date, I know of nobody in Shanghai who has been contacted by the UK consulate for any reason during this outbreak, perhaps the consular staff have already gone home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s about where we stand. Keeping heads down and waiting it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:-)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">Living in Shanghai during the current coronavirus outbreak, I’m often asked by overseas friends, how we are doing. The short form answer to that is, “We’re fine”. But here’s a longer update on the situation to date from the perspective of an expat in Shanghai.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Camera Life 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/a-life-in-cameras-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camera Life 2" /><published>2020-01-31T11:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-01-31T11:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/a-life-in-cameras-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/a-life-in-cameras-2">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/cameras/fed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FED 4 Camera&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second of a series of posts dedicated to the many cameras that I have owned over the years. While some posts may focus on my thoughts about the camera itself, for others, I hope to dig up some remote memories and anecdotes from the time when I owned it.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing this second article has taken a bit longer than expected. The problem is that this article and several future articles will touch on the same subject. It’s not a difficult subject, but I don’t want to start repeating myself without having something new to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought my first &lt;em&gt;serious&lt;/em&gt; camera, a Russian made FED 4 rangefinder, in my late teens. The decision to buy a rangefinder was probably 90% influence from my father. He was a huge fan of Leica and its rangefinders, and he instilled that sentiment in me with his enthusiasm. Sadly, he would never own a Leica although, years later, he did get to play with one of the early Leica digital models when I brought it back from Amsterdam. Maybe I’ll return to that story in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s about it for camera talk in this post. The FED 4 wasn’t a great camera but it served me well for a couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is more about missed opportunities and choices made at that time that can never be rectified. To tell that story, we need to start much more recently. On December 29th, 2019, the famous Scottish author, Alasdair Gray died. I confess that I had never read any of his books and wasn’t fully aware of his status and legacy. However, I did remember, as an 18-year-old student in Glasgow in 1981, seeing his first and most famous novel “Lanark” prominently displayed in the city’s book shops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember being intrigued by this odd looking book with the naked woman on the cover, but I never bought it, because of the naked woman on the cover. As a teenager, still living at home with my parents, I felt that the anticipated explanations required for the inevitable questions that would be asked far outweighed my desire to read the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to January 2020 and I’m looking for something to read. Having read the obituaries for Gray I was now aware that “Lanark” was probably one of the most important and influential works of Scottish literature of the 20th Century so it made sense to finally read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading this book has been an eye-opener. The main character, Thaw is growing up in the Riddrie area of Glasgow during the Second World War. My father grew up in Riddrie at that time. Later, after the war is over, Thaw attends Whitehill Senior Secondary School. In the book, Gray paints a vivid picture of the teaching staff. My father attended Whitehill Senior Secondary School at that time. Thaw’s father takes a job building the reservoir at Hogganfield. My grandparents lived just across the road from what became known as Hogganfield Loch. I remember it well, though I didn’t realise it was such a recent addition to the landscape. A little &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Alasdair_Gray&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; shows that this part of the book semi-autobiographical as it mirrors Gray’s early life. He grew up in Riddrie and attended Whitehill Senior Secondary School at the same time as my father.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/a7/c1/31/a7c1315001ba76f3241159f45760e6a4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px;&quot; title=&quot;Whitehill Senior Secondary School&quot; alt=&quot;Whitehill Senior Secondary School&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many missed opportunities. Had I bought this book when it first came out it would have opened up so many chances to learn about my father’s childhood and education. I would love to know if the teachers described in the book bear any relationship to actual teachers of the period. I’d also love to know if my father was aware of this kid, a couple of years younger than him, who was destined for such literary greatness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, opportunities lost due to the shy reluctance of the teenage me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="cameras" /><category term="photography" /><category term="gas" /><category term="fed" /><category term="rangefinder" /><category term="leicamount" /><category term="Leica" /><category term="biographical" /><category term="Whitehill Senior Secondary School" /><category term="Riddrie" /><category term="Glasgow" /><category term="Alasdair Gray" /><category term="Lanark" /><summary type="html">Second of a series of posts dedicated to the many cameras that I have owned over the years. While some posts may focus on my thoughts about the camera itself, for others, I hope to dig up some remote memories and anecdotes from the time when I owned it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/fed.jpg%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mayflower 400 - Mayflower II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/22/mayflower-400" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mayflower 400 - Mayflower II" /><published>2019-12-22T11:40:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-12-22T11:40:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/22/mayflower-400</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/22/mayflower-400">&lt;p&gt;This morning I learned, through a retweet from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nicklewis&quot;&gt;@NickLewis&lt;/a&gt; of a tweet by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mayflower400uk&quot;&gt;@Mayflower400Uk&lt;/a&gt;, that 2020 will be the 400th anniversary of the voyage of the Mayflower. It reminded me of a family link to the Mayflower and a personal anecdote from about 20 years ago related to that link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/mayflowerII.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mayflower Replica&quot; style=&quot;width: 40%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, the family link is not with the Mayflower that sailed almost 400 years ago, it’s with the Mayflower II replica that made the same crossing in 1957.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mayflower II was built in Brixham, Devon in the mid-1950s. As an aside, I spent many weeks in Brixham in the mid-‘80s, but that’s not the link, maybe I’ll save that for a future post. One of the goals of the Mayflower II was to keep everything as authentic and true to the original as possible. Obviously it was required by law to carry more modern safety devices, but apart from that, everything was as close as possible to a 17th century merchant ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Craftsmen from all over the UK were called to produce the fittings for the ship. One of those fittings was a replica of the captain’s chest for his cabin. This was a rectangular wooden box, about a meter long and perhaps fifty centimetres tall and deep. It was covered by a flat wooden lid attached with two wrought iron hinges. Those hinges were made by my grandfather, James Smith, in Glasgow. At that time, he was running the family business, “R Smith and Co.”, a company that specialised in architectural iron work. Although the company is long gone, some of Glasgow’s most famous buildings are still graced with its wrought ironwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard the story of the hinges on the Mayflower II a few times when I was growing up. My father was posted to Germany in the army at the time they were made so he never saw them. He didn’t think he would ever have the chance to see them so it was just a story to tell the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the late ’90s. I found myself in a job that was taking me to Boston several times a year. I decided to extend one of my trips into a vacation and invited my parents to join me. It was a chance to tour New England and, of course, to visit Plimoth Plantation where the Mayflower II is on display. In the weeks before the trip Dad emailed Plimoth Plantation to ask if it would be possible to see the chest with his father’s hinges. The answer from the museum curator was positive. While the chest wasn’t currently on display, it was in storage and she would be happy to show it to us when we arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at the museum, after touring the Mayflower II, we headed to the admin offices to meet up with the curator that my Dad had been in contact with. She took us in an elevator down into the bowels of the building where we found ourselves in a large, slightly musty smelling, storage room filled with rows of shelving, all stacked with artefacts. She took us to a row where we saw two large, very similar, chests, wrapped in heavy clear plastic for protection. She unwrapped one, and there it was, the 1950s replica chest, complete with my Grandfather’s hinges. We had a good look and took some photos (sadly lost now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were (literally) wrapping up I was slightly confused. Our family story only ever included a single chest so this second chest was a surprise, I asked the curator if she knew anything of its story and where it came from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh yes.” she replied, “That’s the captain’s chest from the original Mayflower.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="history" /><category term="anecdote" /><category term="iron" /><category term="mayflower400" /><summary type="html">This morning I learned, through a retweet from @NickLewis of a tweet by @Mayflower400Uk, that 2020 will be the 400th anniversary of the voyage of the Mayflower. It reminded me of a family link to the Mayflower and a personal anecdote from about 20 years ago related to that link.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chrome Dark Mode</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/23/chrome-dark-mode" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chrome Dark Mode" /><published>2019-10-23T15:55:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-23T15:55:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/23/chrome-dark-mode</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/23/chrome-dark-mode">&lt;p&gt;Google Chrome version 78 has just launched. I was having a look at the “chrome://flags” page and discovered that it’s now possible to enable dark mode for all sites in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, enter “chrome://flags” in the url bar and then, when the page loads, search for “dark”. You should see the two settings shown in the image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img src=”/img/ChromeDarkMode.png” alt=”Chrome Dark Mode “style=”width: 80%;” /&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select one of the choices for &lt;strong&gt;“Force Dark Mode for Web Content”&lt;/strong&gt; from the drop down menu on the right and click the button at the bottom right of the screen to relaunch your browser. I’m not sure what all the options do, but I found that &lt;strong&gt;“Enabled with selective inversion of everything”&lt;/strong&gt; works quite well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to switch it off again, just repeat the above and set the dropdown to &lt;strong&gt;“Disabled”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>FrasSmith</name></author><category term="chrome" /><category term="google" /><category term="DarkMode" /><category term="tips" /><summary type="html">Google Chrome version 78 has just launched. I was having a look at the “chrome://flags” page and discovered that it’s now possible to enable dark mode for all sites in the browser. As mentioned, enter “chrome://flags” in the url bar and then, when the page loads, search for “dark”. You should see the two settings shown in the image below. &amp;lt;img src=”/img/ChromeDarkMode.png” alt=”Chrome Dark Mode “style=”width: 80%;” /&amp;gt; Select one of the choices for “Force Dark Mode for Web Content” from the drop down menu on the right and click the button at the bottom right of the screen to relaunch your browser. I’m not sure what all the options do, but I found that “Enabled with selective inversion of everything” works quite well. If you want to switch it off again, just repeat the above and set the dropdown to “Disabled”. Enjoy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/ChromeDarkMode.png%22%7D" /></entry></feed>