<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-16T15:45:30+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">TramFishers</title><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><entry><title type="html">Camera Life 6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/13/photographing-lightning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camera Life 6" /><published>2020-08-13T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-08-13T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/13/photographing-lightning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/13/photographing-lightning">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/lightning-banner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lightning Flashes Across The Sky&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have been following my sporadic posts about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tramfishers.com/2019/10/17/a-life-in-cameras-1&quot;&gt;Camera Life&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll be aware that I’ve been a camera owner (and therefore a hobbyist photographer) for over fifty years. In that time, I have only managed to photograph lightning successfully twice. Each time I used a different technique and each time I succeeded… eventually.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first thirty years of my photography hobby I shot with 35mm film. Even trying to photograph lightning would be a very wasteful and costly endeavor. Living in the UK didn’t help, lightning just isn’t that common. Later, when I started traveling and spending more time in the tropics I did see more storms, but I was usually working offshore so trying to photograph lightning could easily have used up my whole trip’s film supply with no hope of replenishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until the advent of digital photography in the late twentieth century that photographing lightning became feasible. Even then it took another ten years or so before the right combination of location, climate, and vantage point enabled my first attempt at capturing lightning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;page-subtitle&quot;&gt;First Attempt, August 2010&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/lightning2010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lightning Flashes Across The Sky, August 2010&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, we moved to Shanghai. Our apartment, on the twentieth floor, has a good view south towards the Huangpu River. I was using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dpreview.com/products/ricoh/compacts/ricoh_grdigital3&quot;&gt;Ricoh GRDIII&lt;/a&gt; camera at this time. The little Ricoh certainly wasn’t the ideal camera for this challenge. However, it did have some redeeming features that made capturing the shot easier, if not predictable. After a few failed attempts trying to time my shutter presses with flashes of lightning, I resorted to automation. The Ricoh had a very flexible manual focusing system for a compact camera so I was able to manually focus on infinity and disable the inevitable hunting for focus that would result from trying to use autofocus. I then configured the built-in interval timer to take one shot every five seconds. I walked away and left it on a table-top tripod shooting. I can’t remember whether the SD card filled up or the battery ran out first. However, by the time it stopped shooting, the storm was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On loading several hundred shots into my computer, I had the one keeper and several near misses. I’ve reprocessed the original raw file with my current iPad Pro workflow and I’m pleased to see that it looks even better now than it did ten years ago. Not bad for a ten-megapixel compact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technique: Manually focus on infinity, interval shooting at five seconds, hope that you get lucky.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;page-subtitle&quot;&gt;Second Attempt, August 2020&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.picfair.com/pics/011819435-lightning-over-shanghai&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/lightning2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lightning Flashes Across The Sky, August 2020&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to this year, almost exactly ten years after the first image. Of course there have been many thunderstorms in the intervening years, but none seem to have coincided with me being here to shoot, night-time, and being visible from the southern side of our building. I’m now using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dpreview.com/products/canon/slrs/canon_eosm5&quot;&gt;Canon EOS-M5&lt;/a&gt; mirrorless camera. The M5 is a much more capable camera, especially when paired with the 11-22mm wide-angle zoom. However, it doesn’t support interval shooting so the lazy option I used before wasn’t available this time (I could have used the Canon EOS app to set this up, but it’s not something I use often so I didn’t want to waste time). Instead, the M5 has a reasonably fast multiple shot burst rate of about nine frames per second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that there is often a short pre-flash with some lightning bolts. By setting the lens to manual focus on infinity, again, to eliminate autofocus hunting, I was often able to press and hold the shutter when I first saw a flash and then shoot a burst over the next second or two capturing any subsequent forks of lightning. With a bit of practice, this method was more successful than the previous method and resulted in more successful captures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image above is a composite of two consecutive images about 100ms apart. The first caught the start of the fork as the bolt of lightning shot down from the top left. The second caught the caught multiple branches seeking an earth point. I stacked these two images in Affinity Photo on my iPad Pro and then finished the processing in Pixelmator Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technique: Manually focus on infinity, set the camera to burst shooting, and press and hold the shutter down when you think there’s going to be a fork.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither of these methods is particularly reliable. You will end up with hundreds of exposures of dark skies or glowing clouds. You will also miss some beauties and capture some boring strikes. Such is life. However, if you persevere you can get results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve made a wallpaper version of the second image with a 16:9 aspect ratio available for free download &lt;a href=&quot;https://tramfishers.com/wallpapers&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="tutorial, photography" /><category term="writing" /><category term="write52" /><category term="tutorial" /><category term="photography" /><category term="weather" /><category term="storm" /><category term="lightning" /><summary type="html">If you have been following my sporadic posts about Camera Life, you’ll be aware that I’ve been a camera owner (and therefore a hobbyist photographer) for over fifty years. In that time, I have only managed to photograph lightning successfully twice. Each time I used a different technique and each time I succeeded… eventually.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Time for a Break</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/22/taking-a-break" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time for a Break" /><published>2020-04-22T18:33:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-22T18:33:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/22/taking-a-break</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/22/taking-a-break">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Random people sitting on a bench&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I’d never join a club that would allow a person like me to become a member.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;― Woody Allen&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About fifteen years ago, I discovered that I enjoyed writing. I think I discovered it most when a popular blog shared one of my posts, and I experienced the frisson of a post gaining ten thousand views in twelve hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years later, I had relocated to Shanghai and had an educational startup. I was writing weekly blog posts for this company and enjoying the process. Late in 2010, a twitter friend, (hi &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zee&quot;&gt;@zee&lt;/a&gt;), posted that his company was looking for somebody in Asia to write about tech subjects from Asia. I jumped at the opportunity. While I had worked in the publishing industry for thirteen years, it was in a technical role. I wasn’t a trained journalist. But I enjoyed writing. I felt I could do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenextweb.com&quot;&gt;TNW&lt;/a&gt; in the autumn of 2010 as its “Asia Editor”. How cool is that? An editor. Me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part, in the beginning, I suffered from imposter syndrome, &lt;em&gt;I wasn’t a real writer&lt;/em&gt;. Luckily the team was great and helped the new boy out. However, what I couldn’t get used to was the writing to order. I was expected to publish at least three stories a day, five days a week. The stories didn’t have to be too long but I found the pressure incredible. Especially on Mondays. Tech news usually moves to US West coast time. On Mondays in Asia, not much tech stuff happens until, well, Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other problem was that, before TNW, I wrote about things that interest me. I still do. Working for TNW, there were times when a story came up that had to be written and published within fifteen minutes (to beat &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com&quot;&gt;Techcrunch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com&quot;&gt;Mashable&lt;/a&gt;). Even if the subject matter was of little interest to the average techie (or me), the scoop was the goal, not the subject. I struggled with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months later I was relieved when TNW sacked me (Thanks @zee!). It is the only time in my career that I’ve been sacked and I never expected to feel so happy about it. But I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to the present. I still like writing, on my terms, about subjects that interest me. I’ve been meaning to get back into it more regularly so, last year, I started this site, tramfishers.com (yes, it’s a stupid name, I know. Too late now.), to focus more on written pieces as opposed to the photos that I usually post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, a friend started posting with the #Write52 hashtag. I investigated and found the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.write52.com/&quot;&gt;Write52&lt;/a&gt; project where people try to write and publish one post per week. It sounded like fun. This also coincided with the first weeks of lockdown in China so I also had something to write about. Three months later, and it’s not so much fun anymore. I missed last week completely, despite having three good ideas for posts. The previous week, my whole post was a haiku. The problem is that the drive to come up with something every week has become a chore. It’s no longer fun. So, I’ve decided that this will be my final regular #Write52 post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I going to stop writing? No, after all, I’ve still got three good ideas to write about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s just that I’ll be writing on my terms when I want to. No pressure. Maybe I’ll even tag some future posts as #Write52 in the cheeky hope that I might garner a few views from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="write52" /><category term="tnw" /><category term="TheNextWeb" /><summary type="html">“I’d never join a club that would allow a person like me to become a member.” ― Woody Allen</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Springtime Haiku</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/09/springtime" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Springtime Haiku" /><published>2020-04-09T13:40:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-09T13:40:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/09/springtime</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/09/springtime">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/tree-pollen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tree pollen&quot; /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Shanghai in springtime. &lt;br /&gt;
Tree pollen falling like snow. &lt;br /&gt;
Unseen in winter. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="haiku" /><category term="poetry" /><category term="seasons" /><category term="spring" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Camera Life 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/02/camera-life-5" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camera Life 5" /><published>2020-04-02T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-02T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/02/camera-life-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/02/camera-life-5">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/terragen2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Landscape with Terragen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s hard to believe that a hobby program from a student at York University would be the catalyst to get me back into photography, but that’s exactly what happened in the late nineties. I cannot deny that, photographically, I’d lost my way at that time. In career terms, things were going well, I had left the offshore life in 1994 after a year posted to China and started working in the newspaper industry as an advertising systems engineer. On the personal front, however, it was pretty awful. And that is all that I’m going to say on that subject. It’s water under the bridge.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as long as I had owned computers (about fifteen years or so at this time) I had been interested in using those machines to create photo-realistic rendered images. I was a fan of the work of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Ken_Musgrave&quot;&gt;Ken Musgrave&lt;/a&gt;, a pioneer in the field. The Acorn Archimedes that I bought in 1987 was probably my first computer that could produce realistic images in a practical timeframe. One of my favorite programs on this machine was a BBC basic program called “Magrathea” that, you’ve guessed it, created computer-generated landscapes. It was fun hacking the program to improve the realism of the output, but it couldn’t be called photo realistic in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward about a decade and the world is a different place. Windows 95 is already the dominant operating system and boring beige boxes ruled the roost. I was still into 3D rendering, but, at my level, there was still no realistic landscape generating application at the hobbyist end of the market. It’s at this point that I heard about a beta app created by a student programmer at York University called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/name/nm1232297/&quot;&gt;Matt Fairclough&lt;/a&gt;, his app was called &lt;a href=&quot;https://planetside.co.uk&quot;&gt;Terragen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s this got to do with photography? Bear with me and you’ll find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terragen was everything that I had been looking for. It allowed me to create photo-realistic landscapes (within certain boundaries) on my Windows PC, and it did it well. Not only that but, it also had a very vibrant user community for sharing and discussing creations. I made friends on the Terragen group that remain friends to this day. However, all was not well. When creating my imaginary landscapes, I would often spend hours tweaking viewpoints and compositions to achieve the best possible image. I noticed, at this time, that not everyone took the same care. For many people, the composition took second place to the photo-realistic aspects of their images. Many images looked great but didn’t work as anything but technical demonstrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that my problem was that I was trying to create works that were realistic but also compositionally attractive too. I was trying to render landscape photos. Everywhere I went, I started looking at the landscape with a new eye, an eye to how I would render it. This soon led to me thinking about how I might photograph the landscape. It was time to get back into photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1998, I bought one of the first digital cameras on the market. A Fujifilm DX-7. This was an expensive plastic thing that shot at 640x480 VGA resolution. I have no surviving photos from this camera and my only memory of it is when it seized up from the cold on the summit of Mount Washington in New Hampshire. However, I had the digital bug and soon replaced it with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dpreview.com/reviews/olympusc2500l/&quot;&gt;Olympus C2500L&lt;/a&gt; a much better machine with a massive 2.5-megapixel sensor and a zoom lens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2000, my company wanted to send me to Hong Kong. However, before I could go to Hong Kong, I would have to visit the head office in Boston for some training first. I wasn’t so keen on the idea of flying from London to Boston on a Tuesday, returning to London on Friday and then leaving for Hong Kong on Sunday. So, I suggested that on Friday, I fly to Seattle instead and then onwards to Hong Kong on the following Monday. The company agreed. This would give me a weekend in Washington and a chance to meet up with Terragen friends Tim and Angela O’Donoghue. The first &lt;a href=&quot;http://timster.net/angela//mt-st-helens/index.htm&quot;&gt;Terragen Intercontinental Conference&lt;/a&gt; was born. It was great to discover that Tim also had a C2500L (He reminded me to mention that yesterday).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visit was a success, we went to Mount St. Helens, its landscape still showing signs of devastation twenty years after the eruption. On the second day, Tim and I headed north into the Cascades to photograph the awesome Mount Shuksan and to experience the surreal novelty (for me) of fifteen-foot deep snow-drifts, on a hot sunny July day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second Terragen Intercontinental Conference took place a year later in Los Angeles and coincided with SIGGRAPH2001. This one was truly intercontinental with attendees from the UK, the USA, and New Zealand. Matt (living in LA by this time) was there as was Terragen’s Macintosh coder, Jo, from New Zealand, and Ken Musgrave who was promoting his new product, “Mojoworld” that year. Tim and I still managed to grab a day off From the hectic foot pounding schedule of the exhibition halls and head out to Joshua Tree National Park with our C2500Ls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-1&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-2&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-3&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-4&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-5&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2500-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2500-6&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="cameras" /><category term="photography" /><category term="gas" /><category term="autobiographical" /><category term="Olympus C2500L" /><category term="Olympus" /><category term="Seattle" /><category term="Washington" /><category term="Terragen" /><category term="software" /><summary type="html">It’s hard to believe that a hobby program from a student at York University would be the catalyst to get me back into photography, but that’s exactly what happened in the late nineties. I cannot deny that, photographically, I’d lost my way at that time. In career terms, things were going well, I had left the offshore life in 1994 after a year posted to China and started working in the newspaper industry as an advertising systems engineer. On the personal front, however, it was pretty awful. And that is all that I’m going to say on that subject. It’s water under the bridge.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/terragen.jpg%22%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/terragen.jpg%22%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Life Under Lockdown 6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/25/life-under-lockdown-6" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Under Lockdown 6" /><published>2020-03-25T18:30:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T18:30:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/25/life-under-lockdown-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/25/life-under-lockdown-6">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/empty-road2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An empty road in Shanghai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With most of the world seemingly under lockdown now, I didn’t think there was much scope for another “Life Under Lockdown” post. I was even toying with the idea of a new series, “life After Lockdown” based on the improvements to our situation here in Shanghai. However, events of the last weekend served as a reminder that, even if we’re not totally under lockdown, China is, and it’s getting stricter.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, we’ve been able to get out more for non-essential trips. My wife was on one such trip last Friday. As she returned home, I could see from the app on my phone that the car was parked downstairs, but she didn’t get home for another 40 minutes. When she eventually returned, she explained that there had been an emergency residents’ committee meeting. The son of one of our neighbors would be returning from his studies at a European university the following Sunday so plans had to be formulated for his quarantine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These plans would require the adding of additional surveillance to his parents’ apartment to trigger an alarm with the local police if there was any unauthorized departure. They were taking this seriously. They also decided that one of the building’s two elevators would be off for several hours each day to allow for the collection of household waste and subsequent disinfection of the elevator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday came and, with it, the news that the student would be detained at the airport for 24 hours until his virus check was completed. With so many 10-15 minute tests hitting the market, it seems that the authorities are still using the older, slower tests. Maybe they’re still more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday passed without incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday morning, the excitement started to build. Not only was the famous student returning home, but he would also do so in style. In an ambulance (not so stylish I’ll grant you) with a police escort. As 11:45 drew close everyone was at their windows to see the show, phones at the ready to record the events for posterity. We later found out that the local party chief was in attendance, as were two videographers, to ensure that everything was handled properly and securely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on Monday, the Shanghai government announced that as from March 25th, all arrivals at the airports would be automatically quarantined at government facilities (converted sports halls, I think) for 14 days. I guess that’ll free up the ambulances, police and party chiefs for more important duties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best and take care!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="covid-19" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">With most of the world seemingly under lockdown now, I didn’t think there was much scope for another “Life Under Lockdown” post. I was even toying with the idea of a new series, “life After Lockdown” based on the improvements to our situation here in Shanghai. However, events of the last weekend served as a reminder that, even if we’re not totally under lockdown, China is, and it’s getting stricter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Camera Life 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/18/camera-life-4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camera Life 4" /><published>2020-03-18T18:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-18T18:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/18/camera-life-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/18/camera-life-4">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/cameras/oly-bw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Olympus XA Camera plus film&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nothing could have prepared me for the intense heat and humidity of Houston, Texas, in the late summer of 1984, when I arrived there for my first overseas posting. Even the TV weather forecasts couldn’t cope when screen weather tickers topped out at 99% humidity for the simple reason that they couldn’t handle the three digits required to display 100%.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduating from college in 1983, I spent the summer months working in a Hi-fi shop in Glasgow while I looked for a full-time job. I found that job in the autumn and started my training a few weeks before Christmas. Very early on, I learned that the job would entail a lot of overseas travel and that I would be spending a lot of time at sea. It seemed that traveling light would be the order of the day and I wouldn’t be able to take my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tramfishers.com/2020/03/11/a-life-in-cameras-3&quot;&gt;SLR and lenses&lt;/a&gt; with me on my trips. A smaller camera was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My 21st birthday was in February 1984, so I asked my sister and brother-in-law for a new camera as a birthday gift. The camera that I chose was the very compact and entirely pocketable Olympus XA. I could write hundreds of words about this camera but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.casualphotophile.com/2018/06/20/olympus-xa-review-35mm-film-camera-rangefinder/&quot;&gt;Casual Photo File&lt;/a&gt; does a much better job than I could and I’m not trying to write about cameras per se.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The XA became my carry-everywhere camera for the next fifteen years or so. Right up until I bought my first digital camera in the late nineties. Even since that time I have still run the occasional roll of film through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job was with a company called Racal Survey, although, in many parts of the world, it was still known by its more historically famous name Decca Survey. As an aside Decca Survey was a separate company from Decca Records, the company that infamously rejected The Beatles. Decca Survey was more famous as the company built out of the technological advances in navigation made during World War Two that enabled the thousand bomber raids over Germany by using its accurate (for the time) navigation network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several training courses in the UK and a couple of offshore jobs in the North Sea, I was ready for my first overseas posting, Houston, Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steamy as Houston was, it was nothing compared to the location for my first assignment of that trip. After a week in the office acclimatizing, I was given a pickup truck and sent to look after a system monitoring station on the gulf coast of Louisiana. &lt;img src=&quot;/img/fs-houston.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FS in Houston, 1984&quot; class=&quot;lft&quot; /&gt;The station itself consisted of a 10 m antenna erected at the edge of a small trailer park some ten miles off the main road and a mile or two from the coast. The monitoring equipment was housed in one of the trailers. It turned out that this was where I too was to be housed for the next three weeks. Whoa, three years of study and, a year after graduation, I’m living in a trailer park in rural Louisiana. That was unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life in the trailer park was “interesting”. I soon learned to be careful when putting the trash out as some small black slithery, almost certainly venomous, wildlife liked to hide in the shade under the bin. I was glad to see that they were just as worried about me as I was about them as they disappeared with some speed when exposed. &lt;img src=&quot;/img/gulf-sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset on the Gulf of Mexico 1984&quot; class=&quot;rght&quot; /&gt; Every evening in the dusk, I was entertained by a light show from thousands of fireflies at the edge of the nearby wood. My neighbors told me that there were alligators in the area too although I never managed to see any, even after making a couple of special trips to the places where they were supposed to hang out. I did see a few later in the trip when I had to over-fly the region in a helicopter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also entertained by my trailer park neighbor, Lionel (“Lah’own’eyll”) and his timid wife, Dolly. In the politically incorrect words (even then) of my Texan colleagues, Lionel was a “coon-ass”, the Louisiana equivalent of a “red-neck” in Texas. Basically, he was poor, white, and rural. He was a big man, best described as the human equivalent in stature and speech of &lt;a href=&quot;https://looneytunes.fandom.com/wiki/Foghorn_Leghorn&quot;&gt;Foghorn Leghorn&lt;/a&gt; the Looney Tunes cartoon rooster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lionel, it turned out, liked to do odd jobs and, according to Lionel, my predecessors always paid him $20 to cut the grass around the antenna. I’m not sure if that was entirely true, but I was happy enough to give him the work because it was a large area and the days were hot. This paid off as Lionel then offered to introduce me to the local speciality, gumbo, “dat’s good eat’n boy, good eat’n” is how I remember him describing it to me. What he omitted to explain was that he was going to cook this crab gumbo (an all-day affair) in my trailer, on my stove, using my gas. I think I ended up paying for the crabs as well. No matter, it was good eat’n.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have several more stories from this period maybe I’ll revisit it in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my last &lt;em&gt;successful&lt;/em&gt; outing with the Olympus XA was almost twenty years later in the Netherlands. Long after leaving Racal, I was working on a publishing project in Amsterdam. A dutch friend invited me to join her on a peculiarly dutch activity called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wadlopen.net/&quot;&gt;wadlopen&lt;/a&gt;. On certain days (preferably warm sunny summer days) at low tide, large groups of walkers take to the mud along the north coast of Fryslân and walk across the mudflats to one of the islands that lie a few kilometers off the coast. It’s decidedly muddy and, at times, extremely wet as on some stretches walkers are chest-deep in the sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No way was I going to take my shiny new DSLR on a risky trip like that. So, out came the trusty XA and a few rolls of black and white film. It took most of the day, but we made it to the island of Ameland, tired, wet, and very salty, but not too muddy because the deeper channel had washed the worst off.  Then we had to dash back to the main town on the island to catch the ferry back to the mainland. Wadlopen was a lot more fun than it sounds. A few hours later, back in my apartment in Amsterdam I headed straight into a much-needed shower and immediately tripped getting in, breaking my toe. Such is life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My absolute last outing with the XA was on a photo-walk in Shanghai in 2016. I took the XA and my Fujifilm X100T. During the walk, it was clear that the rangefinder window was misaligned, so I couldn’t trust the focus. I’ve yet to process those films (that’s them in the photo at the top of this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll finish with a few photos of wadlopen in the Netherlands. All the best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 1&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 2&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 3&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 4&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 5&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/wl6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wadlopen 6&quot; class=&quot;pic&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="cameras" /><category term="photography" /><category term="gas" /><category term="autobiographical" /><category term="Olympus XA" /><category term="Olympus" /><category term="Racal" /><category term="Decca" /><category term="houston" /><category term="texas" /><category term="louisiana" /><category term="snakes" /><category term="alligators" /><category term="wadlopen" /><category term="netherlandscode" /><summary type="html">Nothing could have prepared me for the intense heat and humidity of Houston, Texas, in the late summer of 1984, when I arrived there for my first overseas posting. Even the TV weather forecasts couldn’t cope when screen weather tickers topped out at 99% humidity for the simple reason that they couldn’t handle the three digits required to display 100%.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/oly.jpg%22%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/oly.jpg%22%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Camera Life 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/11/a-life-in-cameras-3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camera Life 3" /><published>2020-03-11T17:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-11T17:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/11/a-life-in-cameras-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/11/a-life-in-cameras-3">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/cameras/xgm-banner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Minolta Camera&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I often think of the XG/M as my first SLR camera. It wasn’t. I’d had a Praktica SLR for some time already, but I had no lenses other than the kit lens and it used a screw mount which was notoriously tricky and slow to use. So, the Minolta with its bayonet mount was the first SLR that I had additional lenses for, the first one that I took seriously. However, this post isn’t about that camera (well, maybe it is a little).&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t remember the first time I went to G. E. Williamson’s camera shop in Glasgow’s Sauchiehall Street, but I do know that it was the first of many visits and several purchases. The most significant of these purchases was the Minolta XG/M SLR camera that is, nominally, the subject of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September 1980, I became a student at Glasgow College of Technology (now known as Glasgow Caledonian University). I was lucky to qualify for a student grant, but I also wanted to supplement that with some regular income. I had been given the name of Tom Simmonds, the manager at James Kerr and Co., a high-end Hi-fi shop in Woodlands Road. Over the summer before I started college, I pestered this poor man with multiple phone calls asking if they had any Saturday jobs. At first, he had tried to fob me off by saying that he didn’t know and that I should call back in a week or two. I don’t think he expected me to do that. But I did. A few times. Finally, he invited me in for a chat. And that was it, I had a Saturday job earning the princely sum of £10 per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Williamson’s was nearby and it became a regular stop on my Saturday lunch breaks. In character, it was very similar to Kerr’s. They were both from an older time. A time when wood, not aluminium or steel, was the primary building material for shop furniture. Glass topped counters with narrow wooden frames that doubled as display cases for smaller goods. Smoke had yellowed the walls, visible only between display cases and dog-eared advertising posters. In Williamson’s, the end of the shop was dedicated to tripods and lighting stands, in Kerr’s, to speakers. In both cases, the staff worked there because they were knowledgeable about the products on sale and could spend time with a customer to ensure that they bought the right product. This knowledge and attitude resulted in long term customers and repeat purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time that I worked at James Kerr and Co., the eponymous founder was no longer on the scene. The owner at that time was his co-founder Ted McCosh. Ted was every bit the country gentleman, commuting from a long way out of town. He had a brusque nature and didn’t suffer fools gladly. Ted was a tall, almost gaunt, figure that I never saw wear anything but tweed, regardless of the time of year. He’d march in every morning at around eleven, a huge loose-leaf folder under his arm, with barely a nod to any staff in the shop and head straight to his office in the back where he’d immediately light up one of his Senior Service untipped cigarettes. For the first year or so, I lived in fear of getting on the wrong side of him although I learned later that he could be quite friendly once he got to know you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up working for Kerr’s for several years; Saturdays during term time, and full-time during the holidays. My last dealing with Ted was just before I left to take up a full-time job after graduation. I’d had my eye on an old Thorens TD-150 turntable in the stockroom. It dated from the late ’60s and had been Mr. Lancaster’s (one of our long term regular customers). Ted sold it to me for £13. It was a good buy. I sold it over twenty years later to a man from the BBC for significantly more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s ironic that when I was thinking about this post, which was to be about G. E. Williamson’s, I could remember so many details about the shop and its staff but I couldn’t remember the name. I searched online but found nothing. Finally, I asked my sister if she or my brother-in-law knew? They didn’t, but she suggested I ask Ron Young. Ron was an old friend of the family from that time, a member of the same Scout group as me, and is now a professional photographer. As my sister pointed out, he also worked at that end of town for a while. I found Ron’s email address on his website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ronyoungphotography.co.uk/RON_YOUNG_PHOTOGRAPHY/profile.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Ronald Young Photography”&lt;/a&gt;. Ron did indeed know the name of the shop. He also reminded me of the fact that he had also worked at James Kerr and Co. when he was a student, a few years before me. It was Ron who had given me Tom Simmonds as the person to contact to ask for a job. I also learned from Ron, that Ted McCosh bought his camera equipment from Williamson’s and was friends with George Williamson the founder and owner of that shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a short email conversation, we speculated about what became of Tom and Ted. I managed to find a Daily Telegraph notice online. Ted passed away in 2010 at his home in Lanarkshire. He was 84 years old. As a 17-year-old part-time shop assistant, I had always thought of him as being old. In truth, when I started at Kerr’s, this gruff, scary man, Ted, was 53. Four years younger than I am now. That’s certainly something to make you think.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="cameras" /><category term="photography" /><category term="gas" /><category term="autobiographical" /><category term="Glasgow" /><category term="Minolta XG/M" /><category term="Minolta" /><category term="SLR" /><category term="G. E. Williamsons" /><category term="James Kerr and Co." /><category term="Glasgow" /><summary type="html">I often think of the XG/M as my first SLR camera. It wasn’t. I’d had a Praktica SLR for some time already, but I had no lenses other than the kit lens and it used a screw mount which was notoriously tricky and slow to use. So, the Minolta with its bayonet mount was the first SLR that I had additional lenses for, the first one that I took seriously. However, this post isn’t about that camera (well, maybe it is a little).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/xgm.jpg%22%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22/img/cameras/xgm.jpg%22%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Five Things to do Under Lockdown</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/04/five-things-to-do-under-lockdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five Things to do Under Lockdown" /><published>2020-03-04T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-04T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/04/five-things-to-do-under-lockdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/04/five-things-to-do-under-lockdown">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/garlic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Time to learn to cook some garlic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are at post number 5 about life under lockdown in Shanghai. As the situation shows signs of improvement in China but deteriorates in other countries, I bring you some suggestions, in no particular order of importance, for those about to experience their own life under lockdown.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is probably a no-brainer for anyone who has a job, but finds that they are unable to go to their place of work. I’m lucky, I’m already a remote worker so adjusting to lockdown life hasn’t been difficult for me. My advice to those of you experiencing this for the first time is to “set boundaries”, both physical, and chronological. Try to find a location where you can work uninterrupted by your family and focus on your work. However, just because your place of work is now within your home, that doesn’t mean you have to work at all hours of the day. Try to keep to normal business hours.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Of course, with family at home too and possibly with kids taking part in e-learning program, this may not always be easy. Flexibility will be required.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This has been quite a common pastime for people under lockdown in China. It makes sense. If you’re out at work all day, the last thing you want to do when you get home is spend hours in the kitchen preparing a meal. It’s all too easy to order takeaway or warm up left-overs from the weekend. Suddenly, you find yourself with time on your hands. Why not open that recipe page on your smartphone and have some fun?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I confess that this has applied more to my wife than to me, but I have managed to bake some garlic (Yay! I’m a kitchen hero!) and produce a pretty mean baked spaghetti casserole sort of thing where the ingredients at hand didn’t properly overlap with those required by the recipe. I improvised. Nobody complained, seconds were requested, and we all survived.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep Fit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;No more commute. No more visits to the gym (as if I ever did). All that great(?) new food. It all takes its toll on the waistline. You need to do something to compensate for all the everyday exercise that you’re missing due to lockdown. I have an exercise bike (two years old, very low mileage, one careful owner) that I’ve reluctantly started using again to (in Apple parlance) &lt;em&gt;close my ring&lt;/em&gt; every day. You don’t need a bike, I’m sure you can find your own preferred means to &lt;em&gt;close your ring&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try a new hobby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;You’re going to have time on your hands. Take this as an opportunity try a new hobby or learn something you’ve always wanted to learn but have never had the time for. I’ve always wanted to do more writing. Even a short stint at a reasonably famous tech blog, that let’s be honest, I didn’t enjoy at all (they sacked me, and I was so glad) didn’t kill that desire.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This lockdown plus me hearing about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.write52.com/&quot;&gt;Write52&lt;/a&gt; project at the beginning has resulted in these posts. Five down, forty-seven to go.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch obscure stuff and learn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Ok, this one is a bit obscure. I tend to watch a lot of videos on YouTube in the evenings. Photography and science videos are a favourite. With more time, I found I was running out of my staples and I strayed into geekier territory. It’s great, honestly. I can watch and learn at the same time. For the techies out there I have actually found myself; watching geeks do presentations about ‘vim’ and ‘emacs’; I’ve watched people live stream Windows XP installations; I’ve… well enough. I think I’ve dug a deep enough hole already.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;My point is, there’s lots out there and there’s no harm in following random interests to keep the brain cells ticking over.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;All the best.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="covid-19" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">So here we are at post number 5 about life under lockdown in Shanghai. As the situation shows signs of improvement in China but deteriorates in other countries, I bring you some suggestions, in no particular order of importance, for those about to experience their own life under lockdown.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life Under Lockdown 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/26/life-under-lockdown-4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Under Lockdown 4" /><published>2020-02-26T19:30:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-02-26T19:30:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/26/life-under-lockdown-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/26/life-under-lockdown-4">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/train.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Childrens Train Ride under wraps&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the final update about life under lockdown in Shanghai. While it will probably be a few weeks before normality returns (if it ever does return), there are signs of improvement in Shanghai.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a quiet week in Shanghai with few developments on the virus front. Few developments in this context is a good thing because it literally means no new cases in the city for several days. However, as we hope that China may have passed the peak, it seems the rest of the world is just getting started. A few weeks ago at the start of our lockdown, we discussed whether we should leave the country for the duration. We stayed. One of our concerns was that, wherever we went, the covid-19 virus might follow. Watching the reports of clusters appearing in Europe and elsewhere in Asia, I suspect that we may have made a good call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports of South Korean religious cults actively trying to spread the virus globally (Substantiated? Unsubstantiated? I don’t know at this point) are obviously worrying. More worrying, however, is thinking about how well-prepared western countries are for this epidemic. China is remarkably good at mobilizing its citizens in times of national emergency and simple things like mask wearing come as second nature to a population prepared by urban pollution. I’m not so sure that the major western democracies will be so successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the week that the government relaxed travel restrictions to allow people to finally return to the city after their extended Chinese New Year break and kick-start the economy which was probably hovering on the brink of recession. I read today that rush hour traffic in Shanghai was at 80%-90% of normal this morning. There were even some traffic jams. Mixed blessings I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a slightly more “meta” level, this site and specifically this series of posts got quite a boost yesterday when one of my tweets mentioning it was retweeted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neilhimself&quot;&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt;. This accounted for a nice uplift in views for the posts. Which was nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, will this be my final update in this series? Maybe next week I’ll return to my extremely sparse autobiographical series “A Life in Cameras”. I’m pretty sure that we’ll still be under lockdown here, but our position is becoming less unique. How many more people across the globe will be under lockdown next week?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take care, buy masks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="covid-19" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">Perhaps the final update about life under lockdown in Shanghai. While it will probably be a few weeks before normality returns (if it ever does return), there are signs of improvement in Shanghai.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life Under Lockdown 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/19/life-under-lockdown-3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Under Lockdown 3" /><published>2020-02-19T21:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-02-19T21:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/19/life-under-lockdown-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/19/life-under-lockdown-3">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/empty-road.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An Empty road in Shanghai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I wrote the original post in this series, I assumed it was going to be a single post. After the second, I thought that would be it. However, the situation is always fluid. Things change. So here we are with post number 3.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living under lockdown has become the new normal. We do still get out, but we try to only go out when it’s absolutely essential. In addition, we do have regular deliveries which entail a short walk to the gatehouse for collection. Having read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/02/15/business/china-coronavirus-lockdown.html&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, I guess we’re getting off quite lightly. Our apartment building stands alone in its own small compound. The residents are typically owner/occupiers and it’s small enough that the security staff and building management recognise the residents. The residents of larger, multi-apartment compounds in our neighbourhood don’t have such easy access. Many have instituted a pass system to prove residency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily’s unofficial e-learning began this week. Officially the full e-learning programs will start on March 2nd, but Emily is in an international division that chose to restart schooling, albeit remotely, on the original semester start date. After some initial reticence regarding the use of the video conferencing software, things are off and running. Each day commences with a class meeting with their form teacher before they either have more video lessons, do assignments, or Q&amp;amp;A sessions with their teachers. The workload has been high. Almost too high, but there are signs that this will settle down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charlotte’s elementary school sent out some extra homework to keep her busy. There was an 88 page book filled with Mandarin, English and Mathematics problems, as well as a few more relaxing things to make and do. Thankfully, there was a companion volume of answers for frazzled parents. The pack also included an MP3 file which turned out to be a recording of a patriotic song about all the heroic mums and dads (doctors and nurses) who had gone to Wuhan to fight the virus and care for the sick. Sigh. Propaganda like this is one of the downsides of sending kids to local schools. I’m glad to say that both my daughters (Emily spent 5 years in local primary as well before going to an international division) have enough critical thinking ability to recognise that there are certain aspects of the school system that they can safely ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nationwide travel disruption is now having a significant effect on logistics companies. Here in Shanghai, we had become spoiled by the convenience of being able to order goods before 11am and have them delivered within 6 hours. At first, the lockdown meant that same day delivery became next day delivery. Over the last week this has extended, and extended. For such orders, we now wait 2 or 3 days for warehouse processing and then a couple of days transit. Reduced staffing levels are probably the cause of delays as many employees may not have returned after the extended holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s about all from this week’s update. There are signs that the virus may have peaked: No new cases in Shanghai, for example, for several days. I seem to cope pretty well with the lockdown. I spent the first 10 years of my career working offshore. Life at sea wasn’t a lot different from our current situation although there was a greater chance of drowning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fraser Smith</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="coronavirus" /><category term="covid-19" /><category term="shanghai" /><category term="china" /><category term="lockdown" /><category term="write52" /><summary type="html">When I wrote the original post in this series, I assumed it was going to be a single post. After the second, I thought that would be it. However, the situation is always fluid. Things change. So here we are with post number 3.</summary></entry></feed>